Searching O
for O
Arboliva B-POK
Liko B-PER
Roy B-PER
and O
Mollie B-PERSON
discover O
a O
forest O
devastated O
by O
wildfire O

After O
learning O
the O
story O
of O
the B-ORG
Ancient I-ORG
Adventurer I-ORG
Liko B-PER
is O
faced O
with O
a O
decision O

As O
Friede B-PER
tracks O
suspicious O
activity O
Roy B-PER
comes O
up O
with O
some O
special O
training O
for O
Wattrel B-POK

Liko B-PER
has O
gone O
missing O
so O
Dot B-PER
calls O
on O
a O
celebrity O
connection O
for O
help O

Officially O
a O
trainer O
Dot B-PER
teams O
up O
with O
Quaxly B-POK
to O
help O
take O
back O
Likos O
stolen O
pendant O

Fuecoco B-POK
and O
Wattrel B-POK
arent O
getting O
along O
so O
Roy B-PER
sets O
up O
some O
teamwork O
training O

Friede B-PER
tells O
the B-ORG
Rising I-ORG
Volt I-ORG
Tacklers I-ORG
the O
story O
of O
how O
he O
and O
Captain B-POK
Pikachu I-POK
first O
met O