While O
visiting O
an O
observatory O
run O
by O
Sophocless B-PER
cousin O
the O
classmates O
run O
into O
a O
new O
Pokémon O
Minior O
that O
makes O
a O
connection O
with O
Ashs B-PER
Poipole B-POK

Just O
as O
the O
Champion O
of O
the O
Alola B-ORG
Pokémon I-ORG
League I-ORG
is O
crowned O
an O
Ultra O
Wormhole O
opens O
above O
the O
stadium O
and O
an O
angry O
Guzzlord B-POK
appears O

In O
Pallet B-LOC
Town I-LOC
a O
young O
Ash B-PER
Ketchum I-PER
is O
beside O
himself O
with O
anticipationhes O
going O
to O
Professor B-ORG
Oaks I-ORG
Pokémon I-ORG
Camp I-ORG
But O
when O
the O
day O
arrives O
he O
oversleeps O
and O
Professor B-PER
Oak I-PER
and O
the O
other O
campers O
leave O
without O
him O
Two O
of O
the O
young O
campers O
Goh B-PER
and O
Chloe B-PER
become O
separated O
from O
the O
group O
and O
encounter O
the O
Mythical O
Pokémon O
Mew B-POK
and O
Goh B-PER
vows O
to O
catch O
it O
someday O
Meanwhile O
a O
oncelonely O
Pichu B-POK
is O
spending O
its O
days O
with O
a O
group O
of O
friendly O
Kangaskhan B-POK
but O
when O
the O
time O
comes O
for O
it O
to O
set O
off O
on O
its O
own O
it O
suddenly O
evolves O
into O
Pikachu B-POK
After O
some O
time O
Pikachu B-POK
ends O
up O
at O
Professor B-PER
Oaks I-PER
laband O
the O
rest O
is O
history O

Ash B-PER
and O
Goh B-PER
are O
embarking O
on O
their O
first O
full O
day O
as O
research O
fellows O
at O
Professor B-ORG
Cerises I-ORG
Laboratory I-ORG
and O
the O
excitement O
starts O
right O
away O
Theres O
an O
outbreak O
of O
Ivysaur B-POK
and O
Bulbasaur I-ORG
in O
Vermilion B-LOC
City I-LOC
and O
armed O
with O
their O
new O
Rotom O
Phones O
our O
heroes O
set O
out O
to O
investigate O
It O
turns O
out O
the O
Pokémon B-MISC
are O
trying O
to O
reach O
a O
favorite O
sunbathing O
spot O
but O
the O
land O
is O
now O
a O
construction O
site O
for O
a O
Gym O
Ash B-PER
and O
Goh B-PER
follow O
as O
the O
Pokémon B-MISC
climb O
the O
Gym O
towerbut O
Team B-ORG
Rocket I-ORG
isnt O
far O
behind O
Ash B-PER
Pikachu B-POK
and O
the O
Ivysaur B-POK
send O
the O
trio O
packingand O
then O
our O
heroes O
watch O
in O
awe O
as O
the O
triumphant O
Ivysaur B-POK
evolve O
into O
Venusaur B-POK

Professor B-PER
Cerise I-PER
is O
holding O
a O
Pokémon O
Orienteering O
event O
at O
his O
laboratory O
where O
kids O
will O
go O
through O
various O
spots O
to O
look O
for O
Pokémon B-MISC
Ash B-PER
and O
Goh B-PER
have O
both O
been O
chosen O
a O
leaders O
to O
guide O
the O
children O
around O
Ash B-PER
gets O
really O
focused O
on O
the O
battle O
part O
of O
the O
event O
while O
Goh B-PER
focuses O
on O
catching O
them O
furthering O
their O
dreams O
However O
before O
too O
long O
Lugia B-POK
appears O

Liko B-PER
arrives O
at O
Indigo B-ORG
Academy I-ORG
and O
meets O
her O
partner O
Pokémon B-MISC
Sprigatito B-POK

Friede B-PER
Captain O
Pikachu B-POK
and O
the B-ORG
Rising I-ORG
Volt I-ORG
Tacklers I-ORG
step O
up O
to O
help O
protect O
Liko B-PER