id,french,english,german,japanese,english_entities,french_entities,german_entities,japanese_entities,french_tags,english_tags,german_tags,japanese_tags
362534,"Il y a bien longtemps, dans une petite ville du bord de mer appellée Alto Mare, vivait un vieux couple qui était seul, sans enfant...
Un jour ils trouvirent 2 enfants, un garçon et une fille.
Ce vieux couple aimait au plus profond leurs enfants, et n'auraient jamais souhaités les perdre.
Malheureusement, un sombre nuage s'installa sur Alto Mare, pour des raisons inconnues...
La mère de ces deux enfants se promennaient avec eux en ville, en direction de leur domicile, quand soudain un éclair maléfique frappa la mère, qui mourrut sur le coup...
Les deux enfants se mirent à pleurer leur mère, et comme la légende le dit (ça s'est vu dans Pokémon 1 ou le retour de Mewtwo), ""Les larmes venues du coeur ont des pouvoirs extraordinaires !""...
Juste après leur mort, un second éclair frappa les deux enfants, et furent eux aussi tués sur le coup...
Mais leur tristesse et leur larmes se mirent à former une sphère bleue, la ""Larme venue du coeur""...
Cette sphère aux pouvoirs magiques ressussita les deux enfants en Pokémon : Latias et Latios...","Ash, Misty, and Brock travel to the water city of AltoMare where Ash and Misty compete in the Water Chariot Race which Misty ends up winning. After the race Ash ends up saving a girl from Annie and Oakley, two members of Team Rocket who are in the city to try and capture the Legendary Pokémon, Latios and Latias, for Giovanni. Little does Ash know, but this girl is actually Latias in disguise. Ash follows her back to her secret hideout where he meets her brother Latios. Ash also learns that Latias takes the form of her best friend Bianca. Bianca and her grandfather tell Ash all about Latios and Latias and Ash plays with them. That night, Annie and Oakley invade the hideout and capture Latios and steal the Soul Dew in order to power the D.M.A. Now Latias must find Ash and the others and help to save AltoMare and her brother!","Ash, Pikachu und der Rest der Gang sehen ihre größte Herausforderung entgegen, als zwei hinterlistige Diebinnen den geheimnisvollsten und gefährlichsten aller Kristalle ""Herztropfen"" rauben wollen. Fällt er in ihre Hände, ist die Zerstörung der Wasserstadt Altomare unvermeidbar. Es beginnt ein atemberaubendes Rennen gegen die Zeit, bei dem die letzte Hoffnung auf Latios und Latias ruht, die als Hüter des Kristalls mit magischen Kräften ausgestattet sind.",旅を続けるサトシ達一行は、水の都と呼ばれる美しい町「アルトマーレ」にやって来ていた。サトシとカスミはこの時期に行われるアルトマーレの名物「水上レース」に参加する。レース後に街を観光をしていると、サトシは女の子が襲われているところに遭遇する。助けている途中ではぐれてしまうが、博物館で再び姿を見かけ追いかける。不思議な壁を通り抜けた先の庭園で、その女の子は伝説のポケモン、ラティアスが変身していたと判明する。ラティアスが姿を借りていた少女カノンと、その祖父ボンゴレに、この町に伝わる御伽話を聞かされると、サトシはこの町に忍び寄る不穏を感じ取る。その裏では怪盗姉妹のザンナーとリオンが悪事を企てているのだった。,"{362534: [('Misty', 'PERSON'), ('Brock', 'NORP'), ('AltoMare', 'FAC'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Misty', 'PERSON'), ('the Water Chariot Race', 'ORG'), ('Misty', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'GPE'), ('Annie', 'ORG'), ('Oakley', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Latios', 'PERSON'), ('Latias', 'PERSON'), ('Giovanni', 'ORG'), ('Latias', 'PERSON'), ('Latios', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Latias', 'PERSON'), ('Bianca', 'ORG'), ('Bianca', 'ORG'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Latios', 'PERSON'), ('Latias', 'GPE'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('That night', 'TIME'), ('Annie', 'PERSON'), ('Oakley', 'PERSON'), ('Latios', 'PERSON'), ('the Soul Dew', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Latias', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('AltoMare', 'PRODUCT'), ('Alto Mare', 'PER'), ('Alto Mare', 'PER'), ('ça', 'MISC'), ('Pokémon 1', 'MISC'), ('Mewtwo', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Latias', 'MISC'), ('Latios', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Altomare', 'LOC'), ('Zeit', 'MISC'), ('Latios', 'PER'), ('Latias', 'PER'), ('Kristalls', 'PER'), ('アルトマーレ', 'PRODUCT'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('カスミ', 'PERSON'), ('水上レース', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ラティアス', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('怪盗', 'PERSON')]}","{362534: [('Alto Mare', 'PER'), ('Alto Mare', 'PER'), ('ça', 'MISC'), ('Pokémon 1', 'MISC'), ('Mewtwo', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Latias', 'MISC'), ('Latios', 'PER')]}","{362534: [('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Altomare', 'LOC'), ('Zeit', 'MISC'), ('Latios', 'PER'), ('Latias', 'PER'), ('Kristalls', 'PER')]}","{362534: [('アルトマーレ', 'PRODUCT'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('カスミ', 'PERSON'), ('水上レース', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ラティアス', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('怪盗', 'PERSON')]}","[('Il', 'O'), ('y', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('bien', 'O'), ('longtemps', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('petite', 'O'), ('ville', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('bord', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('mer', 'O'), ('appellée', 'O'), ('Alto', 'B-PER'), ('Mare', 'I-PER'), ('vivait', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('vieux', 'O'), ('couple', 'O'), ('qui', 'O'), ('était', 'O'), ('seul', 'O'), ('sans', 'O'), ('enfant', 'O'), ('Un', 'O'), ('jour', 'O'), ('ils', 'O'), ('trouvirent', 'O'), ('2', 'O'), ('enfants', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('garçon', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('fille', 'O'), ('Ce', 'O'), ('vieux', 'O'), ('couple', 'O'), ('aimait', 'O'), ('au', 'O'), ('plus', 'O'), ('profond', 'O'), ('leurs', 'O'), ('enfants', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('nauraient', 'O'), ('jamais', 'O'), ('souhaités', 'O'), ('les', 'O'), ('perdre', 'O'), ('Malheureusement', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('sombre', 'O'), ('nuage', 'O'), ('sinstalla', 'O'), ('sur', 'O'), ('Alto', 'B-PER'), ('Mare', 'I-PER'), ('pour', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('raisons', 'O'), ('inconnues', 'O'), ('La', 'O'), ('mère', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('ces', 'O'), ('deux', 'O'), ('enfants', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('promennaient', 'O'), ('avec', 'O'), ('eux', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('ville', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('direction', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('domicile', 'O'), ('quand', 'O'), ('soudain', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('éclair', 'O'), ('maléfique', 'O'), ('frappa', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('mère', 'O'), ('qui', 'O'), ('mourrut', 'O'), ('sur', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('coup', 'O'), ('Les', 'O'), ('deux', 'O'), ('enfants', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('mirent', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('pleurer', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('mère', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('comme', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('légende', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('dit', 'O'), ('ça', 'B-MISC'), ('sest', 'O'), ('vu', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('1', 'I-MISC'), ('ou', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('retour', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('Mewtwo', 'B-LOC'), ('Les', 'O'), ('larmes', 'O'), ('venues', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('coeur', 'O'), ('ont', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('pouvoirs', 'O'), ('extraordinaires', 'O'), ('Juste', 'O'), ('après', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('mort', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('second', 'O'), ('éclair', 'O'), ('frappa', 'O'), ('les', 'O'), ('deux', 'O'), ('enfants', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('furent', 'O'), ('eux', 'O'), ('aussi', 'O'), ('tués', 'O'), ('sur', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('coup', 'O'), ('Mais', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('tristesse', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('larmes', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('mirent', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('former', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('sphère', 'O'), ('bleue', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('Larme', 'O'), ('venue', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('coeur', 'O'), ('Cette', 'O'), ('sphère', 'O'), ('aux', 'O'), ('pouvoirs', 'O'), ('magiques', 'O'), ('ressussita', 'O'), ('les', 'O'), ('deux', 'O'), ('enfants', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Latias', 'B-MISC'), ('et', 'O'), ('Latios', 'B-PER')]","[('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('Misty', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Brock', 'B-NORP'), ('travel', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('AltoMare', 'B-PRODUCT'), ('where', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('and', 'O'), ('Misty', 'B-PERSON'), ('compete', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'B-ORG'), ('Water', 'I-ORG'), ('Chariot', 'I-ORG'), ('Race', 'I-ORG'), ('which', 'O'), ('Misty', 'B-PERSON'), ('ends', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('winning', 'O'), ('After', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('race', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('ends', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('saving', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('girl', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('Annie', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Oakley', 'B-PERSON'), ('two', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('members', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-ORG'), ('Rocket', 'I-ORG'), ('who', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('city', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('try', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('capture', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Legendary', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Latios', 'B-PER'), ('and', 'O'), ('Latias', 'B-PER'), ('for', 'O'), ('Giovanni', 'B-ORG'), ('Little', 'O'), ('does', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('know', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('girl', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('actually', 'O'), ('Latias', 'B-PER'), ('in', 'O'), ('disguise', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('follows', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('back', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('secret', 'O'), ('hideout', 'O'), ('where', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('meets', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('brother', 'O'), ('Latios', 'B-PER'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('also', 'O'), ('learns', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Latias', 'B-PER'), ('takes', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('form', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('best', 'O'), ('friend', 'O'), ('Bianca', 'B-ORG'), ('Bianca', 'B-ORG'), ('and', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('grandfather', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('all', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('Latios', 'B-PER'), ('and', 'O'), ('Latias', 'B-PER'), ('and', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('plays', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('them', 'O'), ('That', 'B-TIME'), ('night', 'I-TIME'), ('Annie', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Oakley', 'B-PERSON'), ('invade', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('hideout', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('capture', 'O'), ('Latios', 'B-PER'), ('and', 'O'), ('steal', 'O'), ('the', 'B-WORK_OF_ART'), ('Soul', 'I-WORK_OF_ART'), ('Dew', 'I-WORK_OF_ART'), ('in', 'O'), ('order', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('power', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('DMA', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('Latias', 'B-PER'), ('must', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('others', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('save', 'O'), ('AltoMare', 'B-PRODUCT'), ('and', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('brother', 'O')]","[('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Rest', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Gang', 'O'), ('sehen', 'O'), ('ihre', 'O'), ('größte', 'O'), ('Herausforderung', 'O'), ('entgegen', 'O'), ('als', 'O'), ('zwei', 'O'), ('hinterlistige', 'O'), ('Diebinnen', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('geheimnisvollsten', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('gefährlichsten', 'O'), ('aller', 'O'), ('Kristalle', 'O'), ('Herztropfen', 'O'), ('rauben', 'O'), ('wollen', 'O'), ('Fällt', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('ihre', 'O'), ('Hände', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Zerstörung', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Wasserstadt', 'O'), ('Altomare', 'B-LOC'), ('unvermeidbar', 'O'), ('Es', 'O'), ('beginnt', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('atemberaubendes', 'O'), ('Rennen', 'O'), ('gegen', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Zeit', 'B-MISC'), ('bei', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('letzte', 'O'), ('Hoffnung', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('Latios', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'O'), ('Latias', 'B-PER'), ('ruht', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('als', 'O'), ('Hüter', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('Kristalls', 'B-PER'), ('mit', 'O'), ('magischen', 'O'), ('Kräften', 'O'), ('ausgestattet', 'O'), ('sind', 'O')]","[('旅を続けるサトシ達一行は水の都と呼ばれる美しい町アルトマーレにやって来ていたサトシとカスミはこの時期に行われるアルトマーレの名物水上レースに参加するレース後に街を観光をしているとサトシは女の子が襲われているところに遭遇する助けている途中ではぐれてしまうが博物館で再び姿を見かけ追いかける不思議な壁を通り抜けた先の庭園でその女の子は伝説のポケモンラティアスが変身していたと判明するラティアスが姿を借りていた少女カノンとその祖父ボンゴレにこの町に伝わる御伽話を聞かされるとサトシはこの町に忍び寄る不穏を感じ取るその裏では怪盗姉妹のザンナーとリオンが悪事を企てているのだった', 'O')]"
315865,"Dans la région d'Orudan, alors que Ho-oh survole la vallée, une grande bataille se prépare. Lucario, qui sautant de rocher en rocher, a pu apercevoir deux armées de Pokémon, une rouge et une verte, se faisant face et chargeant l'une et l'autre, pose sa main sur un cristal et prévient son maître Aaron de l'imminence du combat.
Celui-ci saute sur un Roucarnage, et prend la direction de la vallée. Lorsqu'il atteind l'endroit ou Lucario l'attend, il informe le Pokémon légendaire que lui, Aaron, doit se rendre auprès de l'Arbre du Commencement du Monde, pour sauver la planète des ravages de la guerre. En Pokémon loyal, Lucario demande à l'accompagner, mais Aaron brandit son sceptre, et Lucario se transformant en une vague d'énergie, se fait aspirer dans le cristal du sceptre, et regarde s'éloigner son maître, alors que les deux armées entament la bataille au coeur de la vallée...","500 years ago, Sir Aaron was marked as a hero for saving the kingdom of Auray when two opposing armies nearly destoyed it in a war. Now, a festival is held every year in honor of Sir Aaron's deed. After winning a tournament competition, Ash is selected to be this year's Aura Guardian. When a mysterious woman by the name of Kid tracks down Mew, Mew disappears and takes an injured Pikachu and Meowth to the Tree of Beginnings. At the same time, Lucario is set free from the staff Ash holds, mistaking Ash for Aaron. Lucario reveals that Aaron was no hero and abandoned the queen, along with trapping him in the staff. Now, Ash must rely on Lucario's help if he's to make it to the Tree of Beginnings and find Pikachu. Kid tags along too, only wanting to learn Mew's connection to the tree. However, their adventure will cause more damage than intended, and the truth of the events of 500 years ago will finally be revealed!
","Im Cameran Palast wird ein großes Fest zu Ehren des legendären Ritters Sir Aaron gefeiert. Der Höhepunkt ist ein Pokémon Wettbewerb, dessen Sieger den Titel des „Hüter der Aura“ erringen kann. Ash und Pikachu treten an und gewinnen den Kampf. Bei der Siegesfeier bekommt Ash den „Stab des Aaron“ überreicht. Plötzlich hört er aus dem Stab die Stimme des darin eingeschlossenen Lucario. Lucario war das Pokémon von Sir Aaron, der vor langer Zeit auf geheimnisvolle Weise den Palast gerettet und danach Lucario in den Stab gebannt hatte. Während der Feier werden plötzlich Mauzi und Pikachu von Mew entführt, einem Pokémon, das in einer sagenumwobenen Felsformation lebt, die man den „Baum des Anfanges“ nennt.","数百年前、オルドラン城は戦争に巻き込まれる危機に瀕する。城と運命を共にすると誓う女王の元から、その城に仕える波導使いアーロンは弟子のルカリオの元へと立ち去るが、戦いが始まろうとしたまさにその時、世界のはじまりの樹に光が灯り、戦いは防がれるのだった。

現代に至り、アーロンは城を守った波導の勇者の伝説として語り継がれ、オルドラン城ではその年の勇者を決めるためのポケモンバトルの大会が催されていた。その大会へ参加したサトシは見事優勝し、優勝者にのみ握ることの許された「アーロンの杖」を手にする。すると突然杖に光が灯りアーロンの弟子であったはずのルカリオが飛び出してきたのだった。","{315865: [('500 years ago', 'DATE'), ('Aaron', 'PERSON'), ('Auray', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aaron', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('year', 'DATE'), ('Aura Guardian', 'ORG'), ('Mew', 'PERSON'), ('Mew', 'PERSON'), ('Pikachu', 'GPE'), ('the Tree of Beginnings', 'ORG'), ('Lucario', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Aaron', 'PERSON'), ('Lucario', 'PERSON'), ('Aaron', 'PERSON'), ('Ash', 'GPE'), ('Lucario', 'PERSON'), ('the Tree of Beginnings', 'ORG'), ('Pikachu', 'GPE'), ('Mew', 'PERSON'), ('500 years ago', 'DATE'), ('Orudan', 'LOC'), ('Ho-oh', 'MISC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Roucarnage', 'LOC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Arbre du Commencement', 'PER'), ('Monde', 'ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Cameran Palast', 'LOC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Palast', 'LOC'), ('Feier', 'MISC'), ('Mauzi', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Mew', 'PER'), ('Anfanges', 'MISC'), ('数百年前', 'DATE'), ('オルドラン城', 'FAC'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON'), ('灯り', 'ORG'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON'), ('勇者', 'PERSON'), ('オルドラン城', 'FAC'), ('勇者', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('優勝', 'ORDINAL'), ('優勝', 'ORDINAL'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON'), ('灯り', 'MONEY'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON')]}","{315865: [('Orudan', 'LOC'), ('Ho-oh', 'MISC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Roucarnage', 'LOC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Arbre du Commencement', 'PER'), ('Monde', 'ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Lucario', 'PER')]}","{315865: [('Cameran Palast', 'LOC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Lucario', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Aaron', 'PER'), ('Palast', 'LOC'), ('Feier', 'MISC'), ('Mauzi', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Mew', 'PER'), ('Anfanges', 'MISC')]}","{315865: [('数百年前', 'DATE'), ('オルドラン城', 'FAC'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON'), ('灯り', 'ORG'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON'), ('勇者', 'PERSON'), ('オルドラン城', 'FAC'), ('勇者', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('優勝', 'ORDINAL'), ('優勝', 'ORDINAL'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON'), ('灯り', 'MONEY'), ('アーロン', 'PERSON')]}","[('Dans', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('région', 'O'), ('dOrudan', 'O'), ('alors', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('Hooh', 'B-MISC'), ('survole', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('vallée', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('grande', 'O'), ('bataille', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('prépare', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('qui', 'O'), ('sautant', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('rocher', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('rocher', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pu', 'O'), ('apercevoir', 'O'), ('deux', 'O'), ('armées', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('une', 'O'), ('rouge', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('verte', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('faisant', 'O'), ('face', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('chargeant', 'O'), ('lune', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('lautre', 'O'), ('pose', 'O'), ('sa', 'O'), ('main', 'O'), ('sur', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('cristal', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('prévient', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('maître', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('de', 'O'), ('limminence', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('combat', 'O'), ('Celuici', 'O'), ('saute', 'O'), ('sur', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('Roucarnage', 'B-LOC'), ('et', 'O'), ('prend', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('direction', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('vallée', 'O'), ('Lorsquil', 'O'), ('atteind', 'O'), ('lendroit', 'O'), ('ou', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('lattend', 'O'), ('il', 'O'), ('informe', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('légendaire', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('lui', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('doit', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('rendre', 'O'), ('auprès', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('lArbre', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('Commencement', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('Monde', 'B-ORG'), ('pour', 'O'), ('sauver', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('planète', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('ravages', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('guerre', 'O'), ('En', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('loyal', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('demande', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('laccompagner', 'O'), ('mais', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('brandit', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('sceptre', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('se', 'O'), ('transformant', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('vague', 'O'), ('dénergie', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('fait', 'O'), ('aspirer', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('cristal', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('sceptre', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('regarde', 'O'), ('séloigner', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('maître', 'O'), ('alors', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('les', 'O'), ('deux', 'O'), ('armées', 'O'), ('entament', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('bataille', 'O'), ('au', 'O'), ('coeur', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('vallée', 'O')]","[('500', 'B-DATE'), ('years', 'I-DATE'), ('ago', 'I-DATE'), ('Sir', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('was', 'O'), ('marked', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('hero', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('saving', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('kingdom', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Auray', 'B-PERSON'), ('when', 'O'), ('two', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('opposing', 'O'), ('armies', 'O'), ('nearly', 'O'), ('destoyed', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('war', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('festival', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('held', 'O'), ('every', 'O'), ('year', 'B-DATE'), ('in', 'O'), ('honor', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Sir', 'O'), ('Aarons', 'O'), ('deed', 'O'), ('After', 'O'), ('winning', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('tournament', 'O'), ('competition', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('is', 'O'), ('selected', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('years', 'O'), ('Aura', 'B-ORG'), ('Guardian', 'I-ORG'), ('When', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mysterious', 'O'), ('woman', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('name', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Kid', 'O'), ('tracks', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('Mew', 'B-PER'), ('Mew', 'B-PER'), ('disappears', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('takes', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('injured', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('and', 'O'), ('Meowth', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'B-ORG'), ('Tree', 'I-ORG'), ('of', 'I-ORG'), ('Beginnings', 'I-ORG'), ('At', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('same', 'O'), ('time', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('is', 'O'), ('set', 'O'), ('free', 'O'), ('from', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('holds', 'O'), ('mistaking', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('for', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('reveals', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('was', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('hero', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('abandoned', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('queen', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('trapping', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('staff', 'O'), ('Now', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('must', 'O'), ('rely', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('Lucarios', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('if', 'O'), ('hes', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'B-ORG'), ('Tree', 'I-ORG'), ('of', 'I-ORG'), ('Beginnings', 'I-ORG'), ('and', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('Kid', 'O'), ('tags', 'O'), ('along', 'O'), ('too', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('wanting', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('learn', 'O'), ('Mews', 'O'), ('connection', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('tree', 'O'), ('However', 'O'), ('their', 'O'), ('adventure', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('cause', 'O'), ('more', 'O'), ('damage', 'O'), ('than', 'O'), ('intended', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('truth', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('events', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('500', 'B-DATE'), ('years', 'I-DATE'), ('ago', 'I-DATE'), ('will', 'O'), ('finally', 'O'), ('be', 'O'), ('revealed', 'O')]","[('Im', 'O'), ('Cameran', 'B-LOC'), ('Palast', 'B-LOC'), ('wird', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('großes', 'O'), ('Fest', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('Ehren', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('legendären', 'O'), ('Ritters', 'O'), ('Sir', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('gefeiert', 'O'), ('Der', 'O'), ('Höhepunkt', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Wettbewerb', 'O'), ('dessen', 'O'), ('Sieger', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Titel', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('Hüter', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Aura', 'O'), ('erringen', 'O'), ('kann', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('treten', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('gewinnen', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Kampf', 'O'), ('Bei', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Siegesfeier', 'O'), ('bekommt', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('den', 'O'), ('Stab', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('überreicht', 'O'), ('Plötzlich', 'O'), ('hört', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('aus', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('Stab', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Stimme', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('darin', 'O'), ('eingeschlossenen', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('war', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('von', 'O'), ('Sir', 'O'), ('Aaron', 'B-PER'), ('der', 'O'), ('vor', 'O'), ('langer', 'O'), ('Zeit', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('geheimnisvolle', 'O'), ('Weise', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Palast', 'B-LOC'), ('gerettet', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('danach', 'O'), ('Lucario', 'B-PER'), ('in', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Stab', 'O'), ('gebannt', 'O'), ('hatte', 'O'), ('Während', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Feier', 'B-MISC'), ('werden', 'O'), ('plötzlich', 'O'), ('Mauzi', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('von', 'O'), ('Mew', 'B-PER'), ('entführt', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('das', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('einer', 'O'), ('sagenumwobenen', 'O'), ('Felsformation', 'O'), ('lebt', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Baum', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('Anfanges', 'B-MISC'), ('nennt', 'O')]","[('数百年前オルドラン城は戦争に巻き込まれる危機に瀕する城と運命を共にすると誓う女王の元からその城に仕える波導使いアーロンは弟子のルカリオの元へと立ち去るが戦いが始まろうとしたまさにその時世界のはじまりの樹に光が灯り戦いは防がれるのだった', 'O'), ('現代に至りアーロンは城を守った波導の勇者の伝説として語り継がれオルドラン城ではその年の勇者を決めるためのポケモンバトルの大会が催されていたその大会へ参加したサトシは見事優勝し優勝者にのみ握ることの許されたアーロンの杖を手にするすると突然杖に光が灯りアーロンの弟子であったはずのルカリオが飛び出してきたのだった', 'O')]"
4971574,"Dans le Royaume des Diamants souterrain, où de nombreux Strassie vivent, le Pokémon fabuleux Diancie en est le chef. Le Cœur de Diamant qui assure la pérennité du royaume s'éteint peu à peu et Diancie n'est pas encore suffisamment forte pour en créer un nouveau. Alors qu'elle recherche l'aide du Pokémon légendaire Xerneas, Diancie rencontre un groupe de voleurs voulant s'approprier sa capacité à créer des diamants et qui, par la même occasion, réveillent le Pokémon légendaire Yveltal et le tirent de son cocon ! Sacha et ses amis vont-ils parvenir à aider Diancie à découvrir son vrai pouvoir, arrêter la rage destructive d'Yveltal et sauver le Royaume des Diamants ?","When the Mythical Pokémon Diancie cannot figure out how to make a new Heart Diamond to save her kingdom of Carbink subjects, she seeks out the Legendary Life Pokémon Xerneas for help, meeting Ash, Serena, Clemont, and Bonnie on the way, as they help her escape a group of jewel thieves and the unintentional awakening of the Legendary Destruction Pokémon Yveltal.","Das Diamantenreich ist in Gefahr! Denn das Leben des Herz-Diamanten, das das Reich mit Energie versorgt, steht kurz vor seinem Ende. Nun ist es an dem Pokémon Diancie, den legendären Xerneas zu finden, mit dessen Hilfe er einen neuen Herz-Diamanten erschaffen will.",ダイアモンドドメインと呼ばれる地下王国の唯一のエネルギー源であるハートダイアモンドは故障しており、交換する必要があります。 新しいハートダイヤモンドを作って王国を救うことができるのは、王国の王女であるポケモンディアンシーだけですが、彼女にはまだそれを作る力がありません。 ディアンシーは、命を与える伝説のポケモンゼルネアスに会うために旅に出ます。これにより、ディアンシーはハートダイヤモンドを作成する力を発見することができます。 ゼルネアスを何ヶ月も探した後、ディアンシーは見つけた街を探索しに行きます。 彼女はポケモントレーナーのアッシュケッチャムと彼の友人、ピカチュウ、セレナ、クレモント、ボニーに会います。 アッシュと彼の友人たちは、ゼルネアスに会うために彼女の探求にディアンシーに加わります。,"{4971574: [('the Mythical Pokémon Diancie', 'ORG'), ('the Legendary Life Pokémon Xerneas', 'ORG'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Serena', 'GPE'), ('Clemont', 'GPE'), ('Bonnie', 'PERSON'), ('the Legendary Destruction Pokémon Yveltal', 'ORG'), ('Royaume des Diamants souterrain', 'LOC'), ('Strassie', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon fabuleux Diancie', 'LOC'), ('Cœur de Diamant', 'MISC'), ('Diancie', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Xerneas', 'MISC'), ('Diancie', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Yveltal', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Diancie', 'PER'), ('Yveltal', 'LOC'), ('Royaume des Diamants', 'LOC'), ('Herz-Diamanten', 'MISC'), ('Reich', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Diancie', 'PER'), ('Xerneas', 'MISC'), ('Herz-Diamanten', 'MISC'), ('地下王国', 'GPE'), ('ディアンシー', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモンゼルネアス', 'ORG'), ('ディアンシー', 'PERSON'), ('ディアンシー', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('アッシュケッチャム', 'ORG'), ('アッシュ', 'PERSON')]}","{4971574: [('Royaume des Diamants souterrain', 'LOC'), ('Strassie', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon fabuleux Diancie', 'LOC'), ('Cœur de Diamant', 'MISC'), ('Diancie', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Xerneas', 'MISC'), ('Diancie', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Yveltal', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Diancie', 'PER'), ('Yveltal', 'LOC'), ('Royaume des Diamants', 'LOC')]}","{4971574: [('Herz-Diamanten', 'MISC'), ('Reich', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Diancie', 'PER'), ('Xerneas', 'MISC'), ('Herz-Diamanten', 'MISC')]}","{4971574: [('地下王国', 'GPE'), ('ディアンシー', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモンゼルネアス', 'ORG'), ('ディアンシー', 'PERSON'), ('ディアンシー', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('アッシュケッチャム', 'ORG'), ('アッシュ', 'PERSON')]}","[('Dans', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('Royaume', 'B-LOC'), ('des', 'I-LOC'), ('Diamants', 'I-LOC'), ('souterrain', 'I-LOC'), ('où', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('nombreux', 'O'), ('Strassie', 'B-LOC'), ('vivent', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('fabuleux', 'I-LOC'), ('Diancie', 'B-PER'), ('en', 'O'), ('est', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('chef', 'O'), ('Le', 'O'), ('Cœur', 'B-MISC'), ('de', 'I-MISC'), ('Diamant', 'I-MISC'), ('qui', 'O'), ('assure', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('pérennité', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('royaume', 'O'), ('séteint', 'O'), ('peu', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('peu', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('Diancie', 'B-PER'), ('nest', 'O'), ('pas', 'O'), ('encore', 'O'), ('suffisamment', 'O'), ('forte', 'O'), ('pour', 'O'), ('en', 'O'), ('créer', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('nouveau', 'O'), ('Alors', 'O'), ('quelle', 'O'), ('recherche', 'O'), ('laide', 'O'), ('du', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('légendaire', 'O'), ('Xerneas', 'B-MISC'), ('Diancie', 'B-PER'), ('rencontre', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('groupe', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('voleurs', 'O'), ('voulant', 'O'), ('sapproprier', 'O'), ('sa', 'O'), ('capacité', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('créer', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('diamants', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('qui', 'O'), ('par', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('même', 'O'), ('occasion', 'O'), ('réveillent', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('légendaire', 'O'), ('Yveltal', 'B-LOC'), ('et', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('tirent', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('cocon', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('ses', 'O'), ('amis', 'O'), ('vontils', 'O'), ('parvenir', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('aider', 'O'), ('Diancie', 'B-PER'), ('à', 'O'), ('découvrir', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('vrai', 'O'), ('pouvoir', 'O'), ('arrêter', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('rage', 'O'), ('destructive', 'O'), ('dYveltal', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('sauver', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('Royaume', 'B-LOC'), ('des', 'I-LOC'), ('Diamants', 'I-LOC')]","[('When', 'O'), ('the', 'B-ORG'), ('Mythical', 'I-ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'B-PER'), ('Diancie', 'I-PER'), ('cannot', 'O'), ('figure', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('Heart', 'O'), ('Diamond', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('save', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('kingdom', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Carbink', 'O'), ('subjects', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('seeks', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('the', 'B-ORG'), ('Legendary', 'I-ORG'), ('Life', 'I-ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Xerneas', 'B-MISC'), ('for', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('meeting', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-PERSON'), ('Serena', 'B-GPE'), ('Clemont', 'B-GPE'), ('and', 'O'), ('Bonnie', 'B-PERSON'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('help', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('escape', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('jewel', 'O'), ('thieves', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('unintentional', 'O'), ('awakening', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'B-ORG'), ('Legendary', 'I-ORG'), ('Destruction', 'I-ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Yveltal', 'B-LOC')]","[('Das', 'O'), ('Diamantenreich', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Gefahr', 'O'), ('Denn', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('Leben', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('HerzDiamanten', 'B-MISC'), ('das', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('Reich', 'B-LOC'), ('mit', 'O'), ('Energie', 'O'), ('versorgt', 'O'), ('steht', 'O'), ('kurz', 'O'), ('vor', 'O'), ('seinem', 'O'), ('Ende', 'O'), ('Nun', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('es', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-PER'), ('Diancie', 'I-PER'), ('den', 'O'), ('legendären', 'O'), ('Xerneas', 'B-MISC'), ('zu', 'O'), ('finden', 'O'), ('mit', 'O'), ('dessen', 'O'), ('Hilfe', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('einen', 'O'), ('neuen', 'O'), ('HerzDiamanten', 'B-MISC'), ('erschaffen', 'O'), ('will', 'O')]","[('ダイアモンドドメインと呼ばれる地下王国の唯一のエネルギー源であるハートダイアモンドは故障しており交換する必要があります', 'O'), ('新しいハートダイヤモンドを作って王国を救うことができるのは王国の王女であるポケモンディアンシーだけですが彼女にはまだそれを作る力がありません', 'O'), ('ディアンシーは命を与える伝説のポケモンゼルネアスに会うために旅に出ますこれによりディアンシーはハートダイヤモンドを作成する力を発見することができます', 'O'), ('ゼルネアスを何ヶ月も探した後ディアンシーは見つけた街を探索しに行きます', 'O'), ('彼女はポケモントレーナーのアッシュケッチャムと彼の友人ピカチュウセレナクレモントボニーに会います', 'O'), ('アッシュと彼の友人たちはゼルネアスに会うために彼女の探求にディアンシーに加わります', 'O')]"
2323051,Cet épisode résumé les aventures de Sacha depuis le début de l'aventure Diamant et Perle,"A clip show summarizing the important events of the first 47 Diamond and Pearl episodes, including Ash's victories over Roark and Gardenia and the introductions of new rivals Paul and Zoey.",Diese Folge ist ein Rückblick der 10. Staffel und wurde nur in Japan ausgestrahlt.,これまでの冒険を振り返るダイジェスト版となっている。,"{2323051: [('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('47', 'CARDINAL'), ('Diamond', 'PERSON'), ('Pearl', 'GPE'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Roark', 'GPE'), ('Gardenia', 'GPE'), ('Paul', 'PERSON'), ('Zoey', 'PERSON'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Perle', 'MISC'), ('Japan', 'LOC'), ('ダイジェスト', 'ORG')]}","{2323051: [('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Perle', 'MISC')]}","{2323051: [('Japan', 'LOC')]}","{2323051: [('ダイジェスト', 'ORG')]}","[('Cet', 'O'), ('épisode', 'O'), ('résumé', 'O'), ('les', 'O'), ('aventures', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('depuis', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('début', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('laventure', 'O'), ('Diamant', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('Perle', 'B-MISC')]","[('A', 'O'), ('clip', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('summarizing', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('important', 'O'), ('events', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('first', 'B-ORDINAL'), ('47', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('Diamond', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Pearl', 'B-GPE'), ('episodes', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Ashs', 'O'), ('victories', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('Roark', 'B-GPE'), ('and', 'O'), ('Gardenia', 'B-GPE'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('introductions', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('rivals', 'O'), ('Paul', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Zoey', 'B-PERSON')]","[('Diese', 'O'), ('Folge', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('Rückblick', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('Staffel', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('wurde', 'O'), ('nur', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Japan', 'B-LOC'), ('ausgestrahlt', 'O')]","[('これまでの冒険を振り返るダイジェスト版となっている', 'O')]"
9354618,"Koko grandit dans la jungle avec un Zarude solitaire. En rencontrant Sacha et Pikachu, il découvre le monde des humains et apprend que son environnement est menacé.","This is a story of a slighly unusual parent-child relationship involving one Pokémon and one human. In the depths of a jungle in the middle of nowhere, we find Okoya Forest, a Pokémon paradise operating with strict laws. The stubborn and obstinate Zarude lived there with his kin, but one day he discovered a human baby by the riverside.","Koko wächst im Dschungel mit einem Zarude auf. Als er Ash und Pikachu kennenlernt, erfährt er von der Menschenwelt – und einem Vorhaben, das seine Heimat bedroht.",人里離れたジャングルの奥地に、厳しい掟で守られたポケモンたちの楽園・オコヤの森があった。そこへ偶然やって来たサトシとピカチュウの前に、幻のポケモン、ザルードによってポケモンとして育てられた少年ココが現れる。自分のことをポケモンだと信じて疑わないココにとって、初めての「ニンゲンの友達」となるサトシ。そんな中、突如としてオコヤの森に危機が迫り……。,"{9354618: [('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Pokémon', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Okoya Forest', 'ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'ORG'), ('Zarude', 'ORG'), ('one day', 'DATE'), ('Zarude', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'MISC'), ('Koko', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('ジャングル', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT')]}","{9354618: [('Zarude', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'MISC')]}","{9354618: [('Koko', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC')]}","{9354618: [('ジャングル', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT')]}","[('Koko', 'O'), ('grandit', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('jungle', 'O'), ('avec', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('Zarude', 'B-PER'), ('solitaire', 'O'), ('En', 'O'), ('rencontrant', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-MISC'), ('il', 'O'), ('découvre', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('monde', 'O'), ('des', 'O'), ('humains', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('apprend', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('environnement', 'O'), ('est', 'O'), ('menacé', 'O')]","[('This', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('story', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('slighly', 'O'), ('unusual', 'O'), ('parentchild', 'O'), ('relationship', 'O'), ('involving', 'O'), ('one', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('Pokémon', 'B-ORG'), ('and', 'O'), ('one', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('human', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('depths', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('jungle', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('middle', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('nowhere', 'O'), ('we', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('Okoya', 'B-ORG'), ('Forest', 'I-ORG'), ('a', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-ORG'), ('paradise', 'O'), ('operating', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('strict', 'O'), ('laws', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('stubborn', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('obstinate', 'O'), ('Zarude', 'B-PER'), ('lived', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('kin', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('one', 'B-DATE'), ('day', 'I-DATE'), ('he', 'O'), ('discovered', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('human', 'O'), ('baby', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('riverside', 'O')]","[('Koko', 'B-PER'), ('wächst', 'O'), ('im', 'O'), ('Dschungel', 'O'), ('mit', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Zarude', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('Als', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('kennenlernt', 'O'), ('erfährt', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('von', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Menschenwelt', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Vorhaben', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Heimat', 'O'), ('bedroht', 'O')]","[('人里離れたジャングルの奥地に厳しい掟で守られたポケモンたちの楽園オコヤの森があったそこへ偶然やって来たサトシとピカチュウの前に幻のポケモンザルードによってポケモンとして育てられた少年ココが現れる自分のことをポケモンだと信じて疑わないココにとって初めてのニンゲンの友達となるサトシそんな中突如としてオコヤの森に危機が迫り', 'O')]"
9509790,"Sacha et Pikachu font ce qu’ils aiment : voyager dans différents endroits. Mais quand la mère de Sacha lui demande la retrouver dans un Centre Pokémon voisin, il part tout de suite : son père sera là aussi ! En chemin, Sacha se lie d’amitié avec un garçon nommé Sunny, qui finit par le conduire dans un endroit où les Baies abondent, près d’une maison. Là, Sacha rencontre un homme et une femme qui lui révèlent que Sunny est leur fils décédé il y a un an. Sacha leur donne la casquette de Sunny, puis aide Sunny à caresser Pikachu avant qu’ils ne se séparent. Au Centre Pokémon, le père de Sacha est déjà parti, mais il a laissé un cadeau à Sacha : une nouvelle casquette !","Ash travels a mountain pass to a nearby town to meet up with his dad. Along the way, he runs into a mysterious young boy with a keen interest in Pokémon.","Ash und Pikachu tun das, was sie lieben und reisen an verschiedene Orte. Aber als Ashs Mutter ihn bittet, sie in einem nahe gelegenen Pokémon Center zu treffen, macht er sich sofort auf den Weg, denn sein Vater wird auch dort sein! Unterwegs freundet sich Ash mit Sonny an, der ihn zu einem Wald voller Sinelbeeren in der Nähe eines Hauses führt. Dort trifft Ash auf einen Mann und eine Frau, die ihm erzählen, dass Sonny ihr Sohn ist, der vor einem Jahr gestorben ist. Ash gibt ihnen Sonnys Kappe zurück und hilft Sonny dann, Pikachu zu streicheln, bevor sich ihre Wege trennen. Im Pokémon Center erfährt Ash, dass sein Vater bereits abgereist ist. Aber er hat ein Geschenk für Ash zurückgelassen, eine brandneue Kappe!",ポケモンマスターを目指し、旅を続けるサトシとピカチュウ。母ハナコとトナリタウンで会う約束をするが、その道中でロケット団にピカチュウを攫われてしまう。ピカチュウを探すサトシは、不思議な少年・ハルトと出会う―。これは、サトシとピカチュウの冒険の日々の、とある１つの出会いを描いた物語。,"{9509790: [('Pokémon', 'ORG'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Centre', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Sunny', 'PER'), ('Baies', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Sunny', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('casquette de Sunny', 'PER'), ('Sunny', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('qu’', 'LOC'), ('Centre Pokémon', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Center', 'LOC'), ('Unterwegs', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Sonny', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Sonny', 'PER'), ('Sohn', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Sonnys Kappe', 'PER'), ('Sonny', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Center', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('トナリタウン', 'GPE'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('ハルト', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('１つ', 'QUANTITY')]}","{9509790: [('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Centre', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Sunny', 'PER'), ('Baies', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Sunny', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('casquette de Sunny', 'PER'), ('Sunny', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('qu’', 'LOC'), ('Centre Pokémon', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Sacha', 'PER')]}","{9509790: [('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Center', 'LOC'), ('Unterwegs', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Sonny', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Sonny', 'PER'), ('Sohn', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Sonnys Kappe', 'PER'), ('Sonny', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Center', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'ORG')]}","{9509790: [('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('トナリタウン', 'GPE'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('ハルト', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('１つ', 'QUANTITY')]}","[('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('font', 'O'), ('ce', 'O'), ('quils', 'O'), ('aiment', 'O'), ('voyager', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('différents', 'O'), ('endroits', 'O'), ('Mais', 'O'), ('quand', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('mère', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('lui', 'O'), ('demande', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('retrouver', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('Centre', 'B-LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'I-LOC'), ('voisin', 'O'), ('il', 'O'), ('part', 'O'), ('tout', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('suite', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('père', 'O'), ('sera', 'O'), ('là', 'O'), ('aussi', 'O'), ('En', 'O'), ('chemin', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('se', 'O'), ('lie', 'O'), ('damitié', 'O'), ('avec', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('garçon', 'O'), ('nommé', 'O'), ('Sunny', 'B-PER'), ('qui', 'O'), ('finit', 'O'), ('par', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('conduire', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('endroit', 'O'), ('où', 'O'), ('les', 'O'), ('Baies', 'B-MISC'), ('abondent', 'O'), ('près', 'O'), ('dune', 'O'), ('maison', 'O'), ('Là', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('rencontre', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('homme', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('femme', 'O'), ('qui', 'O'), ('lui', 'O'), ('révèlent', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('Sunny', 'B-PER'), ('est', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('fils', 'O'), ('décédé', 'O'), ('il', 'O'), ('y', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('leur', 'O'), ('donne', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('casquette', 'B-PER'), ('de', 'I-PER'), ('Sunny', 'B-PER'), ('puis', 'O'), ('aide', 'O'), ('Sunny', 'B-PER'), ('à', 'O'), ('caresser', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('avant', 'O'), ('quils', 'O'), ('ne', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('séparent', 'O'), ('Au', 'O'), ('Centre', 'B-LOC'), ('Pokémon', 'I-LOC'), ('le', 'O'), ('père', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('est', 'O'), ('déjà', 'O'), ('parti', 'O'), ('mais', 'O'), ('il', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('laissé', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('cadeau', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('une', 'O'), ('nouvelle', 'O'), ('casquette', 'O')]","[('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('travels', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mountain', 'O'), ('pass', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('nearby', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('meet', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('dad', 'O'), ('Along', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('runs', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('mysterious', 'O'), ('young', 'O'), ('boy', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('keen', 'O'), ('interest', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC')]","[('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('und', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('tun', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('lieben', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('reisen', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('verschiedene', 'O'), ('Orte', 'O'), ('Aber', 'O'), ('als', 'O'), ('Ashs', 'O'), ('Mutter', 'O'), ('ihn', 'O'), ('bittet', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('nahe', 'O'), ('gelegenen', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-LOC'), ('Center', 'I-LOC'), ('zu', 'O'), ('treffen', 'O'), ('macht', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('sofort', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Weg', 'O'), ('denn', 'O'), ('sein', 'O'), ('Vater', 'O'), ('wird', 'O'), ('auch', 'O'), ('dort', 'O'), ('sein', 'O'), ('Unterwegs', 'B-MISC'), ('freundet', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('mit', 'O'), ('Sonny', 'B-PER'), ('an', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('ihn', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Wald', 'O'), ('voller', 'O'), ('Sinelbeeren', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Nähe', 'O'), ('eines', 'O'), ('Hauses', 'O'), ('führt', 'O'), ('Dort', 'O'), ('trifft', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('auf', 'O'), ('einen', 'O'), ('Mann', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('eine', 'O'), ('Frau', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('ihm', 'O'), ('erzählen', 'O'), ('dass', 'O'), ('Sonny', 'B-PER'), ('ihr', 'O'), ('Sohn', 'B-PER'), ('ist', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('vor', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Jahr', 'O'), ('gestorben', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('gibt', 'O'), ('ihnen', 'O'), ('Sonnys', 'B-PER'), ('Kappe', 'I-PER'), ('zurück', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('hilft', 'O'), ('Sonny', 'B-PER'), ('dann', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('zu', 'O'), ('streicheln', 'O'), ('bevor', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('ihre', 'O'), ('Wege', 'O'), ('trennen', 'O'), ('Im', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-LOC'), ('Center', 'I-LOC'), ('erfährt', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('dass', 'O'), ('sein', 'O'), ('Vater', 'O'), ('bereits', 'O'), ('abgereist', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('Aber', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('hat', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('Geschenk', 'O'), ('für', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-ORG'), ('zurückgelassen', 'O'), ('eine', 'O'), ('brandneue', 'O'), ('Kappe', 'O')]","[('ポケモンマスターを目指し旅を続けるサトシとピカチュウ母ハナコとトナリタウンで会う約束をするがその道中でロケット団にピカチュウを攫われてしまうピカチュウを探すサトシは不思議な少年ハルトと出会うこれはサトシとピカチュウの冒険の日々のとある１つの出会いを描いた物語', 'O')]"
208594,"Pikachu ne se sent pas bien. Sacha va chez le professeur Seko. Il l'aide à remettre Pikachu sur pied. La team Rocket vient et Sacha l'affronte. Une jeune fille de 10 ans, Flora, a vu cela. Elle va avoir son premier Pokémon, elle décide de prendre un Poussifeu. Elle décide d'accompagner Sacha.","In the land of Hoenn, a girl named May travels to Prof. Birch's lab. She is attacked by a wild ghost pokemon called Duskull. Scared, but unharmed, she travels on her bike to the lab in Littleroot Town.Ash also travels to Littleroot town and signs up for the Hoenn League. Ash arrives in town to discover that Littleroot doesn't have a pokemon center! Ash rushes to the Profesor's lab and talks to one of the assistants. The assistant alerts Prof. Birch and the he assists him.Meanwhile, May arrives at the lab to find that the Prof. isn't there. The assistants tell her that he drove into the woods and she rides after them.In the woods, the prof. tumbles down a cliff and lands on a Pochyena. He is suddenly surrounded by a group of the pokemon and he looks like he is in trouble. Suddenly, May arrives and the prof. tells her to take one of the pokemon out of his bag and use it to battle the Pochyena. She ends up throwing Mudkip. Birch tells Mudkip to do a water gun attack.As May and Prof.Birch find Ash. As the group is about to leave, Team Rocket arrive on the scene in a giant robot. They reintroduce themselves to Ash and let May and the prof. know who they are. Jessie still doesn't care about this mission and James and Meowth do the dirty work as they launch an arm that begins draining Pikachu's energy. However, it accidentely HEALS Pikachu and he uses a super-powered Thunderbolt.Back at the lab, May picks the fire pokemon, Torchic. Prof. Birch gives her a pokedex and she qiuetly says how she really doesn't like Pokemon. May's damaged bike due to Pikachu's thunderbolt makes her angry but she decides to ask Ash if she can go with him on his journey. He says OK and they head over to Oladale town as Ash's journey in Hoenn begins.
","Pikachu wird sehr krank. Da es in Wurzelheim kein Pokémon Center gibt, bittet Ash Professor Birk um seine Hilfe. Pikachu hat zuviel Energie in sich und schwebt in Lebensgefahr. Team Rocket schnappt sich Pikachu. Um sich zu schützen, hat Team Rocket eine Maschine entwickelt, die Pikachu entladen soll. Zum Glück ist das in dem Moment genau die richtige Behandlung für Pikachu. Team Rockets Maschine explodiert, und Pikachu kann gerettet werden. Währenddessen ist Maike bei Professor Birk angekommen. Sie will sich ihr erstes Pokémon abholen, obwohl sie sich eigentlich gar nicht so für Pokémon interessiert. Sie entscheidet sich für ein Flemmli. Maike kann Ash überreden, seine Reise nach Rosaltstadt mit ihr fortzusetzen.","　ポケモンマスターをめざし、まだ見ぬ地、ホウエン地方へ旅立ったサトシとピカチュウ。だが、ピカチュウが高熱を出してしまい、サトシはホウエン地方で有名なポケモン博士、オダマキのもとへ向かう。だがその治療中、われをうしなったピカチュウは外へ逃げ出してしまった。サトシとオダマキ博士もすぐにその後を追う。
　一方、ホウエン地方に住むハルカも、ポケモントレーナーとして旅立つため、ポケモンをもらいにオダマキ博士のもとへやって来ていた。だが、研究所に博士がいないと知り、すぐさま博士の後を追いかけていく。
　はたして逃げ出したピカチュウはぶじなのか?!　そして新たな土地でのいきなりのピンチを、サトシはどう切りぬけるのか!?","{208594: [('Hoenn', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Birch', 'PERSON'), ('Duskull', 'PERSON'), ('Littleroot Town', 'PERSON'), ('Littleroot', 'NORP'), ('the Hoenn League', 'FAC'), ('Littleroot', 'ORG'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Profesor', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Birch', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mudkip', 'PERSON'), ('Mudkip', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Jessie', 'PERSON'), ('James', 'PERSON'), ('Pikachu', 'ORG'), ('HEALS Pikachu', 'PERSON'), ('Thunderbolt', 'PERSON'), ('May', 'PERSON'), ('Torchic', 'PERSON'), ('Birch', 'PERSON'), ('Pokemon', 'ORG'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Pikachu', 'GPE'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Oladale', 'ORG'), ('Ash', 'PERSON'), ('Hoenn', 'GPE'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Seko', 'MISC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Rocket', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Poussifeu', 'ORG'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Wurzelheim', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Center', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'PER'), ('Rocket', 'MISC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Team Rocket', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Team Rockets Maschine', 'ORG'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Maike', 'PER'), ('Birk', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Maike', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Rosaltstadt', 'LOC'), ('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON')]}","{208594: [('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Seko', 'MISC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Rocket', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Poussifeu', 'ORG'), ('Sacha', 'PER')]}","{208594: [('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Wurzelheim', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon Center', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'PER'), ('Rocket', 'MISC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Team Rocket', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Team Rockets Maschine', 'ORG'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Maike', 'PER'), ('Birk', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Maike', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Rosaltstadt', 'LOC')]}","{208594: [('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON')]}","[('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('ne', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('sent', 'O'), ('pas', 'O'), ('bien', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('va', 'O'), ('chez', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('professeur', 'O'), ('Seko', 'B-MISC'), ('Il', 'O'), ('laide', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('remettre', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('sur', 'O'), ('pied', 'O'), ('La', 'O'), ('team', 'O'), ('Rocket', 'B-LOC'), ('vient', 'O'), ('et', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('laffronte', 'O'), ('Une', 'O'), ('jeune', 'O'), ('fille', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('10', 'O'), ('ans', 'O'), ('Flora', 'B-PER'), ('a', 'O'), ('vu', 'O'), ('cela', 'O'), ('Elle', 'O'), ('va', 'O'), ('avoir', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('premier', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('elle', 'O'), ('décide', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('prendre', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('Poussifeu', 'B-ORG'), ('Elle', 'O'), ('décide', 'O'), ('daccompagner', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER')]","[('In', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('land', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('Hoenn', 'B-GPE'), ('a', 'O'), ('girl', 'O'), ('named', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('travels', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Prof', 'O'), ('Birchs', 'O'), ('lab', 'O'), ('She', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('attacked', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('wild', 'O'), ('ghost', 'O'), ('pokemon', 'O'), ('called', 'O'), ('Duskull', 'B-PERSON'), ('Scared', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('unharmed', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('travels', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('bike', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lab', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Littleroot', 'B-ORG'), ('TownAsh', 'O'), ('also', 'O'), ('travels', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Littleroot', 'B-ORG'), ('town', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('signs', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'B-FAC'), ('Hoenn', 'B-GPE'), ('League', 'I-FAC'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('arrives', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('town', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('discover', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('Littleroot', 'B-ORG'), ('doesnt', 'O'), ('have', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pokemon', 'O'), ('center', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('rushes', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Profesors', 'O'), ('lab', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('talks', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('one', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('assistants', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('assistant', 'O'), ('alerts', 'O'), ('Prof', 'O'), ('Birch', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('assists', 'O'), ('himMeanwhile', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('arrives', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lab', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Prof', 'O'), ('isnt', 'O'), ('there', 'O'), ('The', 'O'), ('assistants', 'O'), ('tell', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('drove', 'O'), ('into', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('woods', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('rides', 'O'), ('after', 'O'), ('themIn', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('woods', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prof', 'O'), ('tumbles', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('cliff', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('lands', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Pochyena', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('suddenly', 'O'), ('surrounded', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pokemon', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('looks', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('trouble', 'O'), ('Suddenly', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('arrives', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prof', 'O'), ('tells', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('take', 'O'), ('one', 'B-CARDINAL'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('pokemon', 'O'), ('out', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('bag', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('use', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('battle', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pochyena', 'O'), ('She', 'O'), ('ends', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('throwing', 'O'), ('Mudkip', 'B-PERSON'), ('Birch', 'B-PERSON'), ('tells', 'O'), ('Mudkip', 'B-PERSON'), ('to', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('water', 'O'), ('gun', 'O'), ('attackAs', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('and', 'O'), ('ProfBirch', 'O'), ('find', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('As', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('group', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('leave', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-PER'), ('Rocket', 'I-PER'), ('arrive', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('scene', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('giant', 'O'), ('robot', 'O'), ('They', 'O'), ('reintroduce', 'O'), ('themselves', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('and', 'O'), ('let', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('and', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('prof', 'O'), ('know', 'O'), ('who', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('are', 'O'), ('Jessie', 'B-PERSON'), ('still', 'O'), ('doesnt', 'O'), ('care', 'O'), ('about', 'O'), ('this', 'O'), ('mission', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('James', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('Meowth', 'O'), ('do', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('dirty', 'O'), ('work', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('launch', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('arm', 'O'), ('that', 'O'), ('begins', 'O'), ('draining', 'O'), ('Pikachus', 'O'), ('energy', 'O'), ('However', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('accidentely', 'O'), ('HEALS', 'B-PERSON'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('and', 'O'), ('he', 'O'), ('uses', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('superpowered', 'O'), ('ThunderboltBack', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('lab', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('picks', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('fire', 'O'), ('pokemon', 'O'), ('Torchic', 'B-PERSON'), ('Prof', 'O'), ('Birch', 'B-PERSON'), ('gives', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('pokedex', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('qiuetly', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('how', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('really', 'O'), ('doesnt', 'O'), ('like', 'O'), ('Pokemon', 'B-ORG'), ('Mays', 'O'), ('damaged', 'O'), ('bike', 'O'), ('due', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Pikachus', 'O'), ('thunderbolt', 'O'), ('makes', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('angry', 'O'), ('but', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('decides', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('ask', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('if', 'O'), ('she', 'O'), ('can', 'O'), ('go', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('him', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('journey', 'O'), ('He', 'O'), ('says', 'O'), ('OK', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('over', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Oladale', 'B-ORG'), ('town', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Ashs', 'O'), ('journey', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Hoenn', 'B-GPE'), ('begins', 'O')]","[('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('wird', 'O'), ('sehr', 'O'), ('krank', 'O'), ('Da', 'O'), ('es', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Wurzelheim', 'B-LOC'), ('kein', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Center', 'I-LOC'), ('gibt', 'O'), ('bittet', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Birk', 'B-PER'), ('um', 'O'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Hilfe', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('hat', 'O'), ('zuviel', 'O'), ('Energie', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('schwebt', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('Lebensgefahr', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-PER'), ('Rocket', 'I-PER'), ('schnappt', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('Um', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('schützen', 'O'), ('hat', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-PER'), ('Rocket', 'I-PER'), ('eine', 'O'), ('Maschine', 'O'), ('entwickelt', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('entladen', 'O'), ('soll', 'O'), ('Zum', 'O'), ('Glück', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('Moment', 'O'), ('genau', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('richtige', 'O'), ('Behandlung', 'O'), ('für', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('Team', 'B-ORG'), ('Rockets', 'I-ORG'), ('Maschine', 'I-ORG'), ('explodiert', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('kann', 'O'), ('gerettet', 'O'), ('werden', 'O'), ('Währenddessen', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('Maike', 'B-PER'), ('bei', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Birk', 'B-PER'), ('angekommen', 'O'), ('Sie', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('ihr', 'O'), ('erstes', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('abholen', 'O'), ('obwohl', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('eigentlich', 'O'), ('gar', 'O'), ('nicht', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('für', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('interessiert', 'O'), ('Sie', 'O'), ('entscheidet', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('für', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('Flemmli', 'O'), ('Maike', 'B-PER'), ('kann', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('überreden', 'O'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Reise', 'O'), ('nach', 'O'), ('Rosaltstadt', 'B-LOC'), ('mit', 'O'), ('ihr', 'O'), ('fortzusetzen', 'O')]","[('ポケモンマスターをめざしまだ見ぬ地ホウエン地方へ旅立ったサトシとピカチュウだがピカチュウが高熱を出してしまいサトシはホウエン地方で有名なポケモン博士オダマキのもとへ向かうだがその治療中われをうしなったピカチュウは外へ逃げ出してしまったサトシとオダマキ博士もすぐにその後を追う', 'O'), ('一方ホウエン地方に住むハルカもポケモントレーナーとして旅立つためポケモンをもらいにオダマキ博士のもとへやって来ていただが研究所に博士がいないと知りすぐさま博士の後を追いかけていく', 'O'), ('はたして逃げ出したピカチュウはぶじなのか', 'O'), ('そして新たな土地でのいきなりのピンチをサトシはどう切りぬけるのか', 'O')]"
208596,"Flora essaye de capturer un Azumarill mais sans succès. Mais la Team Magma les attaque. Nos amis vont dans le conduit. Sacha essaye de trouver une sortie mais n'en trouve pas c'est Pikachu qui la trouve! Grâce à un chercheur pokemon, nos amis reprennent leur route pour Clémenti-ville ou Sacha veut gagner son premier badge à Hoenn.","Ash is ready to head to Oldale Town to sign up for the Hoenn League. May has offered to show Ash the way in exchange for his company to Oldale Town - which is only fair, seeing as Pikachu destroyed May's bike when it was sick!  In Oldale Town, May visits her first Pokémon Center and is amazed with all of its services, and by the ancient ruins next door.  Things quickly turn sour when Team Magma, a mysterious band of criminals, shut down the electricity at the Pokémon Center and kidnap Professor Alden in order to invade the ruins.  With no electricity, all of the Pokémon are in danger - including May's Torchic.  It's up to Ash and May to save the day - and in doing so they uncover mysterious ancient Pokémon.
","Mary versucht, ihr erstes Pokémon zu fangen und versagt kläglich. Ash und Mary lernen Professor Aldon kennen. Er erforscht die Ruinen von Rosatstadt. In dem dortigen Steinzimmer soll es ein Tor zur alten Pokémonwelt geben. Auf einer alten Steintafel steht, wie man das alte Steinzimmer betreten kann. Dazu braucht man vier Perlen, die als Schlüssel fungieren. Aber die hat Professor Aldon noch nicht finden können. Plötzlich wird der Professor von einer Bande zwielichtiger Figuren entführt. Auch sie wollen unbedingt in dieses Steinzimmer. Und sie sind im Besitz dieser vier Perlen. Doch die Gauner finden in dem Zimmer nicht die Informationen, nach denen sie gesucht haben, und ziehen wieder ab. Professor Aldon ist begeistert von den Wandmalereien. Zusammen mit Ash und May entdeckt er einen unterirdischen See, in dem ein altes Pokémon, ein Relicanth, schwimmt. Ash und May machen sich auf den Weg nach Blütenburg City. Ash hat sich für die Hoenn Liga registrieren lassen und möchte gegen den dortigen Arenaleiter antreten.","　ホウエン地方での新たな冒険の旅をはじめたサトシとピカチュウ。
　ひょんなことからいっしょに行動することになった新人ポケモントレーナーのハルカと、ホウエンリーグへの参加登録のため、ポケモンセンターのあるコトキタウンをめざしていた。しかし、まだポケモンのあつかいになれないハルカとの道中はドタバタの連続。それでも、なんとかポケモンセンターにたどり着いた一行は、このセンター内でコトキ遺跡を調査しているというウメヅ博士から、古代ポケモンの謎について話を聞くことになる。博士は、その謎を最近といたという。
　その夜、ウメヅ博士とサトシたちは、突然あらわれた複数の男たちにさらわれてしまう。謎の男たちの目的は一体なんなのか!?　そしてコトキ遺跡には何がかくされているのか!?","{208596: [('Oldale Town', 'ORG'), ('the Hoenn League', 'FAC'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Oldale Town', 'PRODUCT'), ('Pikachu', 'GPE'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Oldale Town', 'PRODUCT'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Pokémon Center', 'ORG'), ('Team Magma', 'ORG'), ('the Pokémon Center', 'FAC'), ('Alden', 'GPE'), ('Pokémon', 'ORG'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Ash', 'GPE'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Pokémon', 'ORG'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Azumarill', 'ORG'), ('Team Magma', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Clémenti', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Hoenn', 'PER'), ('Mary', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Mary', 'PER'), ('Aldon', 'PER'), ('Pokémonwelt', 'LOC'), ('Aldon', 'PER'), ('Aldon', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('May', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('May', 'PER'), ('Blütenburg City', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Hoenn Liga', 'ORG'), ('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('新人ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ハルカ', 'PERSON'), ('古代ポケモン', 'DATE'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON')]}","{208596: [('Flora', 'PER'), ('Azumarill', 'ORG'), ('Team Magma', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pikachu', 'LOC'), ('Clémenti', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Hoenn', 'PER')]}","{208596: [('Mary', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Mary', 'PER'), ('Aldon', 'PER'), ('Pokémonwelt', 'LOC'), ('Aldon', 'PER'), ('Aldon', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('May', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('May', 'PER'), ('Blütenburg City', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Hoenn Liga', 'ORG')]}","{208596: [('ホウエン地方', 'LOC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ピカチュウ', 'PERSON'), ('新人ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ハルカ', 'PERSON'), ('古代ポケモン', 'DATE'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON')]}","[('Flora', 'B-PER'), ('essaye', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('capturer', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('Azumarill', 'B-ORG'), ('mais', 'O'), ('sans', 'O'), ('succès', 'O'), ('Mais', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-MISC'), ('Magma', 'I-MISC'), ('les', 'O'), ('attaque', 'O'), ('Nos', 'O'), ('amis', 'O'), ('vont', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('conduit', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('essaye', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('trouver', 'O'), ('une', 'O'), ('sortie', 'O'), ('mais', 'O'), ('nen', 'O'), ('trouve', 'O'), ('pas', 'O'), ('cest', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('qui', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('trouve', 'O'), ('Grâce', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('chercheur', 'O'), ('pokemon', 'O'), ('nos', 'O'), ('amis', 'O'), ('reprennent', 'O'), ('leur', 'O'), ('route', 'O'), ('pour', 'O'), ('Clémentiville', 'O'), ('ou', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('veut', 'O'), ('gagner', 'O'), ('son', 'O'), ('premier', 'O'), ('badge', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('Hoenn', 'B-PER')]","[('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('is', 'O'), ('ready', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('head', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Oldale', 'B-PRODUCT'), ('Town', 'I-PRODUCT'), ('to', 'O'), ('sign', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('the', 'B-FAC'), ('Hoenn', 'B-PER'), ('League', 'I-FAC'), ('May', 'B-PER'), ('has', 'O'), ('offered', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('show', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('the', 'O'), ('way', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('exchange', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('company', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Oldale', 'B-PRODUCT'), ('Town', 'I-PRODUCT'), ('which', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('only', 'O'), ('fair', 'O'), ('seeing', 'O'), ('as', 'O'), ('Pikachu', 'B-LOC'), ('destroyed', 'O'), ('Mays', 'O'), ('bike', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('was', 'O'), ('sick', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('Oldale', 'B-PRODUCT'), ('Town', 'I-PRODUCT'), ('May', 'B-PER'), ('visits', 'O'), ('her', 'O'), ('first', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Center', 'I-ORG'), ('and', 'O'), ('is', 'O'), ('amazed', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('its', 'O'), ('services', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('by', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ancient', 'O'), ('ruins', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('door', 'O'), ('Things', 'O'), ('quickly', 'O'), ('turn', 'O'), ('sour', 'O'), ('when', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-MISC'), ('Magma', 'I-MISC'), ('a', 'O'), ('mysterious', 'O'), ('band', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('criminals', 'O'), ('shut', 'O'), ('down', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('electricity', 'O'), ('at', 'O'), ('the', 'B-FAC'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Center', 'I-FAC'), ('and', 'O'), ('kidnap', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Alden', 'B-GPE'), ('in', 'O'), ('order', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('invade', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('ruins', 'O'), ('With', 'O'), ('no', 'O'), ('electricity', 'O'), ('all', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('are', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('danger', 'O'), ('including', 'O'), ('Mays', 'O'), ('Torchic', 'O'), ('Its', 'O'), ('up', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('and', 'O'), ('May', 'B-PER'), ('to', 'O'), ('save', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('day', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('doing', 'O'), ('so', 'O'), ('they', 'O'), ('uncover', 'O'), ('mysterious', 'O'), ('ancient', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC')]","[('Mary', 'B-PER'), ('versucht', 'O'), ('ihr', 'O'), ('erstes', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('zu', 'O'), ('fangen', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('versagt', 'O'), ('kläglich', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('Mary', 'B-PER'), ('lernen', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Aldon', 'B-PER'), ('kennen', 'O'), ('Er', 'O'), ('erforscht', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Ruinen', 'O'), ('von', 'O'), ('Rosatstadt', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('dortigen', 'O'), ('Steinzimmer', 'O'), ('soll', 'O'), ('es', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('Tor', 'O'), ('zur', 'O'), ('alten', 'O'), ('Pokémonwelt', 'B-LOC'), ('geben', 'O'), ('Auf', 'O'), ('einer', 'O'), ('alten', 'O'), ('Steintafel', 'O'), ('steht', 'O'), ('wie', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('alte', 'O'), ('Steinzimmer', 'O'), ('betreten', 'O'), ('kann', 'O'), ('Dazu', 'O'), ('braucht', 'O'), ('man', 'O'), ('vier', 'O'), ('Perlen', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('als', 'O'), ('Schlüssel', 'O'), ('fungieren', 'O'), ('Aber', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('hat', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Aldon', 'B-PER'), ('noch', 'O'), ('nicht', 'O'), ('finden', 'O'), ('können', 'O'), ('Plötzlich', 'O'), ('wird', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('von', 'O'), ('einer', 'O'), ('Bande', 'O'), ('zwielichtiger', 'O'), ('Figuren', 'O'), ('entführt', 'O'), ('Auch', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('wollen', 'O'), ('unbedingt', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dieses', 'O'), ('Steinzimmer', 'O'), ('Und', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('sind', 'O'), ('im', 'O'), ('Besitz', 'O'), ('dieser', 'O'), ('vier', 'O'), ('Perlen', 'O'), ('Doch', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Gauner', 'O'), ('finden', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('Zimmer', 'O'), ('nicht', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Informationen', 'O'), ('nach', 'O'), ('denen', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('gesucht', 'O'), ('haben', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('ziehen', 'O'), ('wieder', 'O'), ('ab', 'O'), ('Professor', 'O'), ('Aldon', 'B-PER'), ('ist', 'O'), ('begeistert', 'O'), ('von', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Wandmalereien', 'O'), ('Zusammen', 'O'), ('mit', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('May', 'B-PER'), ('entdeckt', 'O'), ('er', 'O'), ('einen', 'O'), ('unterirdischen', 'O'), ('See', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('altes', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('ein', 'O'), ('Relicanth', 'O'), ('schwimmt', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('May', 'B-PER'), ('machen', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Weg', 'O'), ('nach', 'O'), ('Blütenburg', 'B-LOC'), ('City', 'I-LOC'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('hat', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('für', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Hoenn', 'B-ORG'), ('Liga', 'I-ORG'), ('registrieren', 'O'), ('lassen', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('möchte', 'O'), ('gegen', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('dortigen', 'O'), ('Arenaleiter', 'O'), ('antreten', 'O')]","[('ホウエン地方での新たな冒険の旅をはじめたサトシとピカチュウ', 'O'), ('ひょんなことからいっしょに行動することになった新人ポケモントレーナーのハルカとホウエンリーグへの参加登録のためポケモンセンターのあるコトキタウンをめざしていたしかしまだポケモンのあつかいになれないハルカとの道中はドタバタの連続それでもなんとかポケモンセンターにたどり着いた一行はこのセンター内でコトキ遺跡を調査しているというウメヅ博士から古代ポケモンの謎について話を聞くことになる博士はその謎を最近といたという', 'O'), ('その夜ウメヅ博士とサトシたちは突然あらわれた複数の男たちにさらわれてしまう謎の男たちの目的は一体なんなのか', 'O'), ('そしてコトキ遺跡には何がかくされているのか', 'O')]"
208635,"Sacha et ses amis quittent Lavandia, mais Sacha veut se rendre à l'Arène Pokémon de Vermilava, tandis que Flora souhaite participer à un Concours Pokémon à Autequia...","The gang begins on a journey to Fallabor Town, so May can compete in another Contest. In a field on rare Watmel Berries, Ash battles with the protecter of the Watmels to strengthen his Treeko and make it learn new abilities.
","Ash und seine Freunde sind auf dem Weg nach Laubwechselfeld zum nächsten Pokémon-Wettbewerb, als sie plötzlich ein paar herrlich reife Wassermelonen finden. Kurz darauf lernen sie die Melonenmeisterin Natasha kennen, die Ash zu einem Match herausfordert. In der Zwischenzeit macht sich Team Rocket daran, sich Natashas Melonenfeld unter den Nagel zu reißen, doch sie haben nicht mit ihrem Lektroball gerechnet, der ihnen die Suppe gehörig versalzt. Nachdem Team Rocket mal wieder einen Flug in die Umlaufbahn macht, geht der Kampf zwischen Natasha und Ash weiter. Ash versucht nun seinem Geckarbor die Kugelsaatattacke zu zeigen. Doch das stellt sich als ziemlich schwieriges Unterfangen heraus und Geckarbor verliert. Schließlich gelingt es Ash doch noch, Geckarbor dazu zu bringen, eine ordentliche Kugelsaatattacke vom Stapel zu lassen…","　キンセツでのジム戦を終えたサトシたちは、ハルカのポケモンコンテストのためにハジツゲタウンへむかうことに。一行はとちゅうの川でながれてきたスイカを見つけ、ひろって食べようとする。ところが、そこにサトシたちをスイカどろぼうだと思いこんだ少女ナッチがあらわれ、マグマッグとジュプトルでこうげきしてきた！
　なんとかナッチのかんちがいをといた一行は、ナッチのスイカ畑にまねかれた。そしてサトシとナッチは、畑のすみにあるバトルフィールドでダブルバトルをすることに。ところがそのバトル中、スイカをぬすもうとするロケット団があらわれて…。","{208635: [('Fallabor Town', 'ORG'), ('May', 'DATE'), ('Watmel Berries', 'PERSON'), ('Watmels', 'ORG'), ('Treeko', 'PERSON'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Lavandia', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Arène Pokémon de Vermilava', 'PER'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Concours Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Autequia', 'LOC'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon-Wettbewerb', 'MISC'), ('Natasha', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'MISC'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Natashas Melonenfeld', 'PER'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Natasha', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ハルカ', 'GPE'), ('ハジツゲタウン', 'GPE'), ('スイカ', 'GPE'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ナッチ', 'PERSON'), ('ナッチ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ナッチ', 'PERSON'), ('スイカ', 'GPE'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG')]}","{208635: [('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Lavandia', 'MISC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Arène Pokémon de Vermilava', 'PER'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Concours Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Autequia', 'LOC')]}","{208635: [('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Pokémon-Wettbewerb', 'MISC'), ('Natasha', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'MISC'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Natashas Melonenfeld', 'PER'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Natasha', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'LOC')]}","{208635: [('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ハルカ', 'GPE'), ('ハジツゲタウン', 'GPE'), ('スイカ', 'GPE'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ナッチ', 'PERSON'), ('ナッチ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ナッチ', 'PERSON'), ('スイカ', 'GPE'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG')]}","[('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('ses', 'O'), ('amis', 'O'), ('quittent', 'O'), ('Lavandia', 'B-MISC'), ('mais', 'O'), ('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('veut', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('rendre', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('lArène', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'O'), ('de', 'O'), ('Vermilava', 'O'), ('tandis', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('Flora', 'B-PER'), ('souhaite', 'O'), ('participer', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('Concours', 'B-MISC'), ('Pokémon', 'I-MISC'), ('à', 'O'), ('Autequia', 'B-LOC')]","[('The', 'O'), ('gang', 'O'), ('begins', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('journey', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Fallabor', 'B-ORG'), ('Town', 'I-ORG'), ('so', 'O'), ('May', 'B-DATE'), ('can', 'O'), ('compete', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('another', 'O'), ('Contest', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('field', 'O'), ('on', 'O'), ('rare', 'O'), ('Watmel', 'B-PERSON'), ('Berries', 'I-PERSON'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('battles', 'O'), ('with', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('protecter', 'O'), ('of', 'O'), ('the', 'O'), ('Watmels', 'B-ORG'), ('to', 'O'), ('strengthen', 'O'), ('his', 'O'), ('Treeko', 'B-PERSON'), ('and', 'O'), ('make', 'O'), ('it', 'O'), ('learn', 'O'), ('new', 'O'), ('abilities', 'O')]","[('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Freunde', 'O'), ('sind', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('dem', 'O'), ('Weg', 'O'), ('nach', 'O'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'B-LOC'), ('zum', 'O'), ('nächsten', 'O'), ('PokémonWettbewerb', 'B-MISC'), ('als', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('plötzlich', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('paar', 'O'), ('herrlich', 'O'), ('reife', 'O'), ('Wassermelonen', 'O'), ('finden', 'O'), ('Kurz', 'O'), ('darauf', 'O'), ('lernen', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Melonenmeisterin', 'O'), ('Natasha', 'B-LOC'), ('kennen', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('zu', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Match', 'O'), ('herausfordert', 'O'), ('In', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Zwischenzeit', 'O'), ('macht', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-ORG'), ('Rocket', 'I-ORG'), ('daran', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('Natashas', 'B-PER'), ('Melonenfeld', 'I-PER'), ('unter', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Nagel', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('reißen', 'O'), ('doch', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('haben', 'O'), ('nicht', 'O'), ('mit', 'O'), ('ihrem', 'O'), ('Lektroball', 'O'), ('gerechnet', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('ihnen', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Suppe', 'O'), ('gehörig', 'O'), ('versalzt', 'O'), ('Nachdem', 'O'), ('Team', 'B-ORG'), ('Rocket', 'I-ORG'), ('mal', 'O'), ('wieder', 'O'), ('einen', 'O'), ('Flug', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Umlaufbahn', 'O'), ('macht', 'O'), ('geht', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Kampf', 'O'), ('zwischen', 'O'), ('Natasha', 'B-LOC'), ('und', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('weiter', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('versucht', 'O'), ('nun', 'O'), ('seinem', 'O'), ('Geckarbor', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Kugelsaatattacke', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('zeigen', 'O'), ('Doch', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('stellt', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('als', 'O'), ('ziemlich', 'O'), ('schwieriges', 'O'), ('Unterfangen', 'O'), ('heraus', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('Geckarbor', 'O'), ('verliert', 'O'), ('Schließlich', 'O'), ('gelingt', 'O'), ('es', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-LOC'), ('doch', 'O'), ('noch', 'O'), ('Geckarbor', 'O'), ('dazu', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('bringen', 'O'), ('eine', 'O'), ('ordentliche', 'O'), ('Kugelsaatattacke', 'O'), ('vom', 'O'), ('Stapel', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('lassen', 'O')]","[('キンセツでのジム戦を終えたサトシたちはハルカのポケモンコンテストのためにハジツゲタウンへむかうことに一行はとちゅうの川でながれてきたスイカを見つけひろって食べようとするところがそこにサトシたちをスイカどろぼうだと思いこんだ少女ナッチがあらわれマグマッグとジュプトルでこうげきしてきた', 'O'), ('なんとかナッチのかんちがいをといた一行はナッチのスイカ畑にまねかれたそしてサトシとナッチは畑のすみにあるバトルフィールドでダブルバトルをすることにところがそのバトル中スイカをぬすもうとするロケット団があらわれて', 'O')]"
208636,Sacha et ses amis font la connaissance d'un nouveau Pokémon qui semble avoir été blessé. Ils le conduisent dans un centre d'aromathérapie...,"While resting next to Lake May, the gang spots a Volbeat and an Illumise practising for an upcoming dance contest. However a practice session goes wrong and Illumise suddenly vanishes.
","Auf ihrem Weg nach Laubwechselfeld legen Ash und seine Freunde am Maike-See eine kleine Pause ein, weil dort das Mai-Festival stattfinden wird. Dort treffen sie auf Romeo, der es nicht schafft, Julia seine Liebe zu gestehen. Darum versuchen sie ihm mit allen Mitteln zu helfen. Team Rocket ist natürlich auch in der Gegend und will sich die Pokémon Illumise und die Volbeat von Romeo und Julia unter den Nagel reißen. Es gelingt ihnen, Illumise mit einem Trick zu entführen, doch ihr Glück ist nicht von langer Dauer. Dank unserer Helden ist Illumise bald wieder frei und Jesse, James und Mauzi haben wieder einmal das Nachsehen. Außerdem findet Romeo endlich den Mut, Julia seine Liebe zu gestehen…",　サトシたちはハルカ湖とよばれる湖のほとりにある町へとやって来た。そこでは間もなく行われるというおまつりにむけて、ロミオはバルビート、ジュリエはイルミーゼと、それぞれのポケモンとともにダンスのれんしゅうにはげんでいた。ところがロミオは、バルビートへのしじをミスしてしまい、なさけないすがたをサトシたちに見せてしまうことに…。聞けばロミオはジュリエ、バルビートはイルミーゼにそれぞれ恋をしているらしく、目の前でダンスをするのは相手をいしきするあまり、ふだんの実力が出せないのだという。そこでサトシたちは、ロミオ＆バルビートの手だすけをすることにするが…。,"{208636: [('Lake May', 'FAC'), ('Illumise', 'NORP'), ('Illumise', 'LOC'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Maike-See', 'LOC'), ('Mai-Festival', 'LOC'), ('Julia', 'PER'), ('Rocket', 'MISC'), ('Pokémon Illumise', 'MISC'), ('Romeo', 'LOC'), ('Julia unter den Nagel', 'MISC'), ('Jesse', 'PER'), ('James', 'PER'), ('Mauzi', 'LOC'), ('Romeo', 'PER'), ('Julia', 'PER'), ('gestehen…', 'MISC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ハルカ湖', 'LOC'), ('ロミオ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ロミオ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ロミオ＆バルビート', 'ORG')]}","{208636: [('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC')]}","{208636: [('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Maike-See', 'LOC'), ('Mai-Festival', 'LOC'), ('Julia', 'PER'), ('Rocket', 'MISC'), ('Pokémon Illumise', 'MISC'), ('Romeo', 'LOC'), ('Julia unter den Nagel', 'MISC'), ('Jesse', 'PER'), ('James', 'PER'), ('Mauzi', 'LOC'), ('Romeo', 'PER'), ('Julia', 'PER'), ('gestehen…', 'MISC')]}","{208636: [('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ハルカ湖', 'LOC'), ('ロミオ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ロミオ', 'PERSON'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ロミオ＆バルビート', 'ORG')]}","[('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('ses', 'O'), ('amis', 'O'), ('font', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('connaissance', 'O'), ('dun', 'O'), ('nouveau', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('qui', 'O'), ('semble', 'O'), ('avoir', 'O'), ('été', 'O'), ('blessé', 'O'), ('Ils', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('conduisent', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('centre', 'O'), ('daromathérapie', 'O')]","[('While', 'O'), ('resting', 'O'), ('next', 'O'), ('to', 'O'), ('Lake', 'B-FAC'), ('May', 'I-FAC'), ('the', 'O'), ('gang', 'O'), ('spots', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('Volbeat', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('Illumise', 'B-LOC'), ('practising', 'O'), ('for', 'O'), ('an', 'O'), ('upcoming', 'O'), ('dance', 'O'), ('contest', 'O'), ('However', 'O'), ('a', 'O'), ('practice', 'O'), ('session', 'O'), ('goes', 'O'), ('wrong', 'O'), ('and', 'O'), ('Illumise', 'B-LOC'), ('suddenly', 'O'), ('vanishes', 'O')]","[('Auf', 'O'), ('ihrem', 'O'), ('Weg', 'O'), ('nach', 'O'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'B-LOC'), ('legen', 'O'), ('Ash', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'O'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Freunde', 'O'), ('am', 'O'), ('MaikeSee', 'B-LOC'), ('eine', 'O'), ('kleine', 'O'), ('Pause', 'O'), ('ein', 'O'), ('weil', 'O'), ('dort', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('MaiFestival', 'B-LOC'), ('stattfinden', 'O'), ('wird', 'O'), ('Dort', 'O'), ('treffen', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('auf', 'O'), ('Romeo', 'B-PER'), ('der', 'O'), ('es', 'O'), ('nicht', 'O'), ('schafft', 'O'), ('Julia', 'B-PER'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Liebe', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('gestehen', 'B-MISC'), ('Darum', 'O'), ('versuchen', 'O'), ('sie', 'O'), ('ihm', 'O'), ('mit', 'O'), ('allen', 'O'), ('Mitteln', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('helfen', 'O'), ('Team', 'O'), ('Rocket', 'B-MISC'), ('ist', 'O'), ('natürlich', 'O'), ('auch', 'O'), ('in', 'O'), ('der', 'O'), ('Gegend', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('will', 'O'), ('sich', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('Illumise', 'I-MISC'), ('und', 'O'), ('die', 'O'), ('Volbeat', 'O'), ('von', 'O'), ('Romeo', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'O'), ('Julia', 'B-PER'), ('unter', 'I-MISC'), ('den', 'I-MISC'), ('Nagel', 'I-MISC'), ('reißen', 'O'), ('Es', 'O'), ('gelingt', 'O'), ('ihnen', 'O'), ('Illumise', 'O'), ('mit', 'O'), ('einem', 'O'), ('Trick', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('entführen', 'O'), ('doch', 'O'), ('ihr', 'O'), ('Glück', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('nicht', 'O'), ('von', 'O'), ('langer', 'O'), ('Dauer', 'O'), ('Dank', 'O'), ('unserer', 'O'), ('Helden', 'O'), ('ist', 'O'), ('Illumise', 'O'), ('bald', 'O'), ('wieder', 'O'), ('frei', 'O'), ('und', 'O'), ('Jesse', 'B-PER'), ('James', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'O'), ('Mauzi', 'B-LOC'), ('haben', 'O'), ('wieder', 'O'), ('einmal', 'O'), ('das', 'O'), ('Nachsehen', 'O'), ('Außerdem', 'O'), ('findet', 'O'), ('Romeo', 'B-PER'), ('endlich', 'O'), ('den', 'O'), ('Mut', 'O'), ('Julia', 'B-PER'), ('seine', 'O'), ('Liebe', 'O'), ('zu', 'O'), ('gestehen', 'B-MISC')]","[('サトシたちはハルカ湖とよばれる湖のほとりにある町へとやって来たそこでは間もなく行われるというおまつりにむけてロミオはバルビートジュリエはイルミーゼとそれぞれのポケモンとともにダンスのれんしゅうにはげんでいたところがロミオはバルビートへのしじをミスしてしまいなさけないすがたをサトシたちに見せてしまうことに聞けばロミオはジュリエバルビートはイルミーゼにそれぞれ恋をしているらしく目の前でダンスをするのは相手をいしきするあまりふだんの実力が出せないのだというそこでサトシたちはロミオバルビートの手だすけをすることにするが', 'O')]"
208637,"Sacha, Flora, Max et Pierre font la connaissance d'un Draby qui ne rêve que d'une chose : apprendre à voler...","While walking through a mountainous area, the gang encounter a Bagon, who is attempting to realize its life long dream to fly in the skies.
","Ash und seine Freunde sind immer noch unterwegs nach Laubwechselfeld und treffen in den Bergen auf Michelle und Kindwurm, ihr Pokémon, das unbedingt Fliegen lernen will. Da es einen steinharten Schädel hat, ist Team Rocket stark an ihm interessiert. Sie wollen das Kindwurm ihrem Boss schenken. Sie versuchen das Pokémon zu entführen, stoßen aber dabei auf erhebliche Schwierigkeiten, da Ash und seine Freunde ihnen einen Strich durch die Rechnung machen. Schließlich erfüllt sich Kindwurms Traum vom Fliegen, und gemeinsam mit Geckarbor gelingt es ihm, Team Rocket in die Umlaufbahn zu befördern…",　ハジツゲタウンに向かうサトシたちはがけの斜面にある山道を歩いていた。そこで一行は突然(とつぜん)がけの上から飛び降りてくる不思議な“いしあたまポケモン”タツベイと出会う。サトシはポケモンの持ち主ミッチェルに会い、タツベイは“空を飛びたい”と思っている事を知る…。タツベイは進化してボーマンダになれば確実(かくじつ)に空を飛べるようになるので、早く進化させてあげようとサトシはバトルを始めることに。しかしバトル中にロケット団があらわれ、タツベイを連れていってしまう…。タツベイの運命は！？　はたして進化せずに空を飛べるようになるのだろうか！？,"{208637: [('Bagon', 'GPE'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Max', 'PER'), ('Pierre', 'MISC'), ('Draby', 'PER'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Bergen', 'LOC'), ('Michelle', 'LOC'), ('Kindwurm', 'LOC'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Kindwurms', 'PER'), ('Geckarbor', 'PER'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('…', 'PER'), ('いしあたまポケモン', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ミッチェル', 'GPE'), ('空を飛びたい', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG')]}","{208637: [('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Flora', 'PER'), ('Max', 'PER'), ('Pierre', 'MISC'), ('Draby', 'PER')]}","{208637: [('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Bergen', 'LOC'), ('Michelle', 'LOC'), ('Kindwurm', 'LOC'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Pokémon', 'MISC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Kindwurms', 'PER'), ('Geckarbor', 'PER'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('…', 'PER')]}","{208637: [('いしあたまポケモン', 'ORG'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('ミッチェル', 'GPE'), ('空を飛びたい', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG')]}","[('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('Flora', 'B-PER'), ('Max', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('Pierre', 'B-MISC'), ('font', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('connaissance', 'O'), ('dun', 'O'), ('Draby', 'B-PER'), ('qui', 'O'), ('ne', 'O'), ('rêve', 'O'), ('que', 'O'), ('dune', 'O'), ('chose', 'O'), ('apprendre', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('voler', 'O')]","[('While', 'B-PER'), ('walking', 'B-PER'), ('through', 'B-PER'), ('a', 'B-PER'), ('mountainous', 'B-PER'), ('area', 'B-PER'), ('the', 'B-PER'), ('gang', 'B-PER'), ('encounter', 'B-PER'), ('a', 'B-PER'), ('Bagon', 'B-PER'), ('who', 'B-PER'), ('is', 'B-PER'), ('attempting', 'B-PER'), ('to', 'B-PER'), ('realize', 'B-PER'), ('its', 'B-PER'), ('life', 'B-PER'), ('long', 'B-PER'), ('dream', 'B-PER'), ('to', 'B-PER'), ('fly', 'B-PER'), ('in', 'B-PER'), ('the', 'B-PER'), ('skies', 'B-PER')]","[('Ash', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'B-PER'), ('seine', 'B-PER'), ('Freunde', 'B-PER'), ('sind', 'B-PER'), ('immer', 'B-PER'), ('noch', 'B-PER'), ('unterwegs', 'B-PER'), ('nach', 'B-PER'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'B-PER'), ('treffen', 'B-PER'), ('in', 'B-PER'), ('den', 'B-PER'), ('Bergen', 'B-PER'), ('auf', 'B-PER'), ('Michelle', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'B-PER'), ('Kindwurm', 'B-PER'), ('ihr', 'B-PER'), ('Pokémon', 'B-PER'), ('das', 'B-PER'), ('unbedingt', 'B-PER'), ('Fliegen', 'B-PER'), ('lernen', 'B-PER'), ('will', 'B-PER'), ('Da', 'B-PER'), ('es', 'B-PER'), ('einen', 'B-PER'), ('steinharten', 'B-PER'), ('Schädel', 'B-PER'), ('hat', 'B-PER'), ('ist', 'B-PER'), ('Team', 'B-PER'), ('Rocket', 'B-PER'), ('stark', 'B-PER'), ('an', 'B-PER'), ('ihm', 'B-PER'), ('interessiert', 'B-PER'), ('Sie', 'B-PER'), ('wollen', 'B-PER'), ('das', 'B-PER'), ('Kindwurm', 'B-PER'), ('ihrem', 'B-PER'), ('Boss', 'B-PER'), ('schenken', 'B-PER'), ('Sie', 'B-PER'), ('versuchen', 'B-PER'), ('das', 'B-PER'), ('Pokémon', 'B-PER'), ('zu', 'B-PER'), ('entführen', 'B-PER'), ('stoßen', 'B-PER'), ('aber', 'B-PER'), ('dabei', 'B-PER'), ('auf', 'B-PER'), ('erhebliche', 'B-PER'), ('Schwierigkeiten', 'B-PER'), ('da', 'B-PER'), ('Ash', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'B-PER'), ('seine', 'B-PER'), ('Freunde', 'B-PER'), ('ihnen', 'B-PER'), ('einen', 'B-PER'), ('Strich', 'B-PER'), ('durch', 'B-PER'), ('die', 'B-PER'), ('Rechnung', 'B-PER'), ('machen', 'B-PER'), ('Schließlich', 'B-PER'), ('erfüllt', 'B-PER'), ('sich', 'B-PER'), ('Kindwurms', 'B-PER'), ('Traum', 'B-PER'), ('vom', 'B-PER'), ('Fliegen', 'B-PER'), ('und', 'B-PER'), ('gemeinsam', 'B-PER'), ('mit', 'B-PER'), ('Geckarbor', 'B-PER'), ('gelingt', 'B-PER'), ('es', 'B-PER'), ('ihm', 'B-PER'), ('Team', 'B-PER'), ('Rocket', 'B-PER'), ('in', 'B-PER'), ('die', 'B-PER'), ('Umlaufbahn', 'B-PER'), ('zu', 'B-PER'), ('befördern', 'B-PER')]","[('ハジツゲタウンに向かうサトシたちはがけの斜面にある山道を歩いていたそこで一行は突然とつぜんがけの上から飛び降りてくる不思議ないしあたまポケモンタツベイと出会うサトシはポケモンの持ち主ミッチェルに会いタツベイは空を飛びたいと思っている事を知るタツベイは進化してボーマンダになれば確実かくじつに空を飛べるようになるので早く進化させてあげようとサトシはバトルを始めることにしかしバトル中にロケット団があらわれタツベイを連れていってしまうタツベイの運命は', 'O'), ('はたして進化せずに空を飛べるようになるのだろうか', 'O')]"
208638,"Sacha et ses amis se retrouvent dans un étrange royaume, où tout le monde semble être à la recherche d'un Togepi...","Misty arrives in Hoenn, however her reunion with Ash and Brock is cut short when an evil Colonel kidnaps Togepi with the help of Team Rocket.
","Ash und seine Freunde sind immer noch unterwegs nach Laubwechselfeld und treffen unterwegs auf Misty und ihr Pokémon, das Togepi. Kurz darauf wird Togepi von Jessie und James in einem Luftschiff entführt. Aber Ash und seine Truppe sind als Passagiere mit an Bord. Als sie in einem geheimnisvollen Königreich eintreffen, wartet dort bereits der verbrecherische Colonel Hansen, der das Togepi unbedingt braucht, weil er bei der anschließenden Krönungszeremonie die Nachfolge auf den Thron antreten will. Der jetzige König und seine Tochter Sarah erfahren erst jetzt von Hansens Plänen und geraten in arge Bedrängnis. Ash und seine Freunde tun alles, um den beiden zu helfen, doch Hansen und seine Komplizen versuchen mit aller Macht, sein Vorhaben in die Tat umzusetzen…","　ハジツゲタウンをめざすサトシたちは、とちゅうの砂ばくにあるオアシスで、カスミとトゲピーにひさしぶりに会うやくそくをしていた。カスミはオアシスのホテルでひらかれるトゲピー祭りにさんかしようとしていたのだが、実行委員（じっこういいん）にへんそうしたロケット団にだまされてしまいトゲピーはミラージュ王国という国へとさらわれてしまう！
　どうやら、ミラージュ王国にとってトゲピーは王さまをきめるのにひつようなポケモンだという。あとをおったサトシたちは、トゲピーをりようして王さまになることをねらう摂政（せっしょう）のハンゾウと出会い、バトルになるが…。","{208638: [('Hoenn', 'GPE'), ('Ash', 'GPE'), ('Brock', 'GPE'), ('Togepi', 'ORG'), ('Team Rocket', 'ORG'), ('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Togepi', 'MISC'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Misty', 'PER'), ('Togepi von Jessie', 'PER'), ('James', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'ORG'), ('Hansen', 'LOC'), ('Togepi', 'LOC'), ('Krönungszeremonie', 'LOC'), ('Nachfolge', 'LOC'), ('Sarah', 'PER'), ('Hansens', 'PER'), ('arge Bedrängnis', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Hansen', 'PER'), ('…', 'MISC'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('オアシス', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('カスミ', 'PERSON'), ('カスミ', 'PERSON'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG'), ('ミラージュ王国', 'GPE'), ('ミラージュ王国', 'GPE'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ハンゾウ', 'PERSON')]}","{208638: [('Sacha', 'PER'), ('Togepi', 'MISC')]}","{208638: [('Laubwechselfeld', 'LOC'), ('Misty', 'PER'), ('Togepi von Jessie', 'PER'), ('James', 'PER'), ('Ash', 'ORG'), ('Hansen', 'LOC'), ('Togepi', 'LOC'), ('Krönungszeremonie', 'LOC'), ('Nachfolge', 'LOC'), ('Sarah', 'PER'), ('Hansens', 'PER'), ('arge Bedrängnis', 'LOC'), ('Ash', 'PER'), ('Hansen', 'PER'), ('…', 'MISC')]}","{208638: [('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('オアシス', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('カスミ', 'PERSON'), ('カスミ', 'PERSON'), ('ロケット団', 'ORG'), ('ミラージュ王国', 'GPE'), ('ミラージュ王国', 'GPE'), ('ポケモン', 'PRODUCT'), ('サトシ', 'PERSON'), ('ハンゾウ', 'PERSON')]}","[('Sacha', 'B-PER'), ('et', 'O'), ('ses', 'O'), ('amis', 'O'), ('se', 'O'), ('retrouvent', 'O'), ('dans', 'O'), ('un', 'O'), ('étrange', 'O'), ('royaume', 'O'), ('où', 'O'), ('tout', 'O'), ('le', 'O'), ('monde', 'O'), ('semble', 'O'), ('être', 'O'), ('à', 'O'), ('la', 'O'), ('recherche', 'O'), ('dun', 'O'), ('Togepi', 'B-MISC')]","[('Misty', 'B-MISC'), ('arrives', 'B-MISC'), ('in', 'B-MISC'), ('Hoenn', 'B-MISC'), ('however', 'B-MISC'), ('her', 'B-MISC'), ('reunion', 'B-MISC'), ('with', 'B-MISC'), ('Ash', 'B-MISC'), ('and', 'B-MISC'), ('Brock', 'B-MISC'), ('is', 'B-MISC'), ('cut', 'B-MISC'), ('short', 'B-MISC'), ('when', 'B-MISC'), ('an', 'B-MISC'), ('evil', 'B-MISC'), ('Colonel', 'B-MISC'), ('kidnaps', 'B-MISC'), ('Togepi', 'B-MISC'), ('with', 'B-MISC'), ('the', 'B-MISC'), ('help', 'B-MISC'), ('of', 'B-MISC'), ('Team', 'B-MISC'), ('Rocket', 'B-MISC')]","[('Ash', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('seine', 'B-MISC'), ('Freunde', 'B-MISC'), ('sind', 'B-MISC'), ('immer', 'B-MISC'), ('noch', 'B-MISC'), ('unterwegs', 'B-MISC'), ('nach', 'B-MISC'), ('Laubwechselfeld', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('treffen', 'B-MISC'), ('unterwegs', 'B-MISC'), ('auf', 'B-MISC'), ('Misty', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('ihr', 'B-MISC'), ('Pokémon', 'B-MISC'), ('das', 'B-MISC'), ('Togepi', 'B-MISC'), ('Kurz', 'B-MISC'), ('darauf', 'B-MISC'), ('wird', 'B-MISC'), ('Togepi', 'B-MISC'), ('von', 'B-MISC'), ('Jessie', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('James', 'B-MISC'), ('in', 'B-MISC'), ('einem', 'B-MISC'), ('Luftschiff', 'B-MISC'), ('entführt', 'B-MISC'), ('Aber', 'B-MISC'), ('Ash', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('seine', 'B-MISC'), ('Truppe', 'B-MISC'), ('sind', 'B-MISC'), ('als', 'B-MISC'), ('Passagiere', 'B-MISC'), ('mit', 'B-MISC'), ('an', 'B-MISC'), ('Bord', 'B-MISC'), ('Als', 'B-MISC'), ('sie', 'B-MISC'), ('in', 'B-MISC'), ('einem', 'B-MISC'), ('geheimnisvollen', 'B-MISC'), ('Königreich', 'B-MISC'), ('eintreffen', 'B-MISC'), ('wartet', 'B-MISC'), ('dort', 'B-MISC'), ('bereits', 'B-MISC'), ('der', 'B-MISC'), ('verbrecherische', 'B-MISC'), ('Colonel', 'B-MISC'), ('Hansen', 'B-MISC'), ('der', 'B-MISC'), ('das', 'B-MISC'), ('Togepi', 'B-MISC'), ('unbedingt', 'B-MISC'), ('braucht', 'B-MISC'), ('weil', 'B-MISC'), ('er', 'B-MISC'), ('bei', 'B-MISC'), ('der', 'B-MISC'), ('anschließenden', 'B-MISC'), ('Krönungszeremonie', 'B-MISC'), ('die', 'B-MISC'), ('Nachfolge', 'B-MISC'), ('auf', 'B-MISC'), ('den', 'B-MISC'), ('Thron', 'B-MISC'), ('antreten', 'B-MISC'), ('will', 'B-MISC'), ('Der', 'B-MISC'), ('jetzige', 'B-MISC'), ('König', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('seine', 'B-MISC'), ('Tochter', 'B-MISC'), ('Sarah', 'B-MISC'), ('erfahren', 'B-MISC'), ('erst', 'B-MISC'), ('jetzt', 'B-MISC'), ('von', 'B-MISC'), ('Hansens', 'B-MISC'), ('Plänen', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('geraten', 'B-MISC'), ('in', 'B-MISC'), ('arge', 'B-MISC'), ('Bedrängnis', 'B-MISC'), ('Ash', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('seine', 'B-MISC'), ('Freunde', 'B-MISC'), ('tun', 'B-MISC'), ('alles', 'B-MISC'), ('um', 'B-MISC'), ('den', 'B-MISC'), ('beiden', 'B-MISC'), ('zu', 'B-MISC'), ('helfen', 'B-MISC'), ('doch', 'B-MISC'), ('Hansen', 'B-MISC'), ('und', 'B-MISC'), ('seine', 'B-MISC'), ('Komplizen', 'B-MISC'), ('versuchen', 'B-MISC'), ('mit', 'B-MISC'), ('aller', 'B-MISC'), ('Macht', 'B-MISC'), ('sein', 'B-MISC'), ('Vorhaben', 'B-MISC'), ('in', 'B-MISC'), ('die', 'B-MISC'), ('Tat', 'B-MISC'), ('umzusetzen', 'B-MISC')]","[('ハジツゲタウンをめざすサトシたちはとちゅうの砂ばくにあるオアシスでカスミとトゲピーにひさしぶりに会うやくそくをしていたカスミはオアシスのホテルでひらかれるトゲピー祭りにさんかしようとしていたのだが実行委員じっこういいんにへんそうしたロケット団にだまされてしまいトゲピーはミラージュ王国という国へとさらわれてしまう', 'O'), ('どうやらミラージュ王国にとってトゲピーは王さまをきめるのにひつようなポケモンだというあとをおったサトシたちはトゲピーをりようして王さまになることをねらう摂政せっしょうのハンゾウと出会いバトルになるが', 'O')]"
208639,"Avec l'aide de la Team Rocket, le colonel Hansen met tout en oeuvre pour s'emparer de Togepi et ainsi devenir le souverain du Royaume du Mirage...","Cornered by Colonel Hanson and Team Rocket, the gang are amazed when they see Togepi's amazing power in defending them. After escaping, Togepi takes the gang to a dimension populated by unhappy Togepi which has caused the land to grow weak. However when Misty's Togepi is captured by Hanson in order for him to rule the Mirage Island, it leads to a confrontation during which Togepi undergoes the ultimate transformation...
","Ash und seine Freunde gelangen durch einen Zufall in das Togepi Paradies. Alle Togepi werden hier geboren, bevor sie ausziehen, um die Herzen der Menschen zu erobern. Das Togepi Paradies und das Mirage Kingdom haben sich immer gegenseitig beschützt und leben in einem empfindlichen Gleichgewicht. Doch jetzt geht es den dort lebenden Togepi und der Natur sehr schlecht, da das Gleichgewicht durch die Zustände im Mirage Kingdom gestört ist. Colonel Hansen gelingt es mit Hilfe eines geschwächten Togepi, das ein Symbol der königlichen Macht darstellt, den Königsthron an sich zu reißen. Er ruft sich zum König aus. Den alten König lässt er in Haft nehmen. Maike fordert Hansen zu einem Kampf heraus, doch ihr Flemmli ist zu schwach für Hansens Pokémon. Daraufhin greifen die Togepi aus dem Togepi Paradies in den Kampf ein. Mistys Togepi entwickelt sich dabei zu Togetic weiter. Misty setzt schließlich ihr Garados ein und gewinnt den Kampf. Der alte König wird befreit und Colonel Hansen aus dem Königreich geworfen. Die Togepi kehren glücklich in ihr Paradies zurück. Togetic verabschiedet sich schweren Herzens von Misty, weil es das Togepi Paradies beschützen will. Prinzessin Sarah übernimmt die Thronfolge von ihrem Vater und wird zur neuen Königin ernannt. Die Freunde versprechen Misty, die wieder zurück nach Azuria City muss, sie bald zu besuchen.","　ミラージュ王国のつぎの国王になろうとしているハンゾウのワナによって、宮殿（きゅうでん）へとやって来たカスミとサトシたち。 彼らは、そこで出会ったセーラ姫にたすけてもらい、トゲピーといっしょに国の外へだっしゅつしようとしていた。しかし一行は、ハンゾウのヌケニン、テッカニンにおそわれ、トゲピーをうばわれてしまう。
