Still O
on O
the O
way O
to O
Fallabor B-LOC
Town I-LOC
Ash B-PER
and O
friends O
encounter O
their O
friend O
Nicolai B-PER
who O
now O
has O
a O
Zangoose B-POK
in O
his O
Team B-ORG
However O
Team B-ORG
Rocket I-ORG
attack O
during O
the O
battle O
but O
the O
plan O
to O
capture O
Pikachu B-POK
is O
forgotten O
when O
Zangoose B-POK
and O
Seviper B-POK
begin O
a O
fierce O
battle O
stemming O
from O
animosity O
between O
the O
two O
species O
When O
Zangoose B-POK
is O
injured O
Nicolai B-PER
tends O
to O
his O
injured O
Pokemon B-MISC
while O
Jessie B-PER
turns O
Pokemon B-MISC
trainer O
to O
Seviper B-POK
for O
the O
inevitable O
rematch O