With O
their O
adventures O
in O
Lavaridge B-LOC
Town I-LOC
over O
the O
gang O
decide O
to O
head O
back O
through O
Mauville B-LOC
City I-LOC
to O
Petalburg B-LOC
City I-LOC
so O
Ash B-PER
can O
rechallenge O
Norman B-PER
to O
a O
proper O
Gym O
battle O
Ash B-PER
rememebering O
Pikachu B-POK
being O
beaten O
up O
by O
Vigaroth B-POK
is O
eager O
to O
get O
back O
to O
prove O
himself O
as O
a O
worthy O
trainer O
Before O
they O
get O
too O
far O
however O
the O
gang O
encounter O
a O
group O
of O
Spinda B-POK
a O
Pokemon B-MISC
known O
for O
having O
unique O
markings O
on O
their O
face O
Soon O
they O
are O
helping O
a O
girl O
find O
a O
Spinda B-POK
which O
has O
a O
heartshaped O
mark O
on O
its O
face O
and O
Team B-ORG
Rocket I-ORG
are O
looking O
for O
the O
same O
one O
to O
use O
as O
bait O
for O
Pikachu B-POK