The O
gang O
finally O
arrives O
at O
Lilycove B-LOC
City I-LOC
When O
they O
sit O
down O
to O
rest O
May B-PER
sees O
a O
poster O
for O
a O
Pokemon B-MISC
ContestShe O
finds O
out O
theyre O
having O
it O
tomorrow O
and O
the O
group O
starts O
moving O
Pikachu B-POK
runs O
off O
and O
when O
they O
find O
Pikachu B-POK
they O
see O
him O
at O
a O
berry O
standAt O
the O
berry O
stand O
they O
see O
a O
young O
girl O
arguing O
with O
a O
manBefore O
they O
get O
to O
check O
it O
out O
a O
guy O
comes O
offering O
free O
samples O
of O
berriesThen O
they O
see O
the O
young O
girl O
strugling O
with O
a O
bag O
of O
berries O
she O
drops O
the O
berries O
but O
before O
they O
hit O
the O
ground O
her O
Grumpig B-POK
lifts O
up O
the O
berries O
with O
its O
Psychic O
before O
they O
hit O
the O
groundMeanwhile O
Team B-ORG
Rocket I-ORG
plans O
to O
steal O
Grumpig B-POK