Ash B-PER
and O
Iris B-PER
arrive O
in O
Striaton B-LOC
City I-LOC
the O
location O
of O
Unovas B-LOC
first O
gym O
When O
they O
arrive O
in O
town O
they O
meet O
a O
boy O
named O
Cilan B-PER
who O
says O
he O
is O
a O
Pokémon B-MISC
Sommelier O
someone O
who O
is O
able O
to O
test O
the O
compatibility O
between O
a O
Pokémon B-MISC
and O
trainer O
He O
leads O
them O
to O
the O
Gym O
where O
it O
is O
revealed O
that O
he O
and O
his O
two O
brothers O
are O
all O
the O
Gym O
Leaders O
of O
Striaton B-LOC
City I-LOC
Will B-PER
Ash B-PER
be O
able O
to O
defeat O
the O
three O
brothers O
and O
win O
his O
first O
badge O